<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Assessment: symptomatic treatment for muscle cramps (an evidence-based review). Report of the Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Katzberg HD, Khan AH, So YT. Assessment: symptomatic treatment for muscle cramps (an evidence-based review): report of the Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2010 Feb 23;74(8):691-6. [36 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=20177124&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American Academy of Neurology (AAN) reaffirmed the currency of the guideline in July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Definitions of the levels of the recommendations (&lt;strong&gt;A, B, C, U&lt;/strong&gt;) and classification of the evidence (&lt;strong&gt;Class I-IV&lt;/strong&gt;) are provided at the end of the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question 1: Are there effective nonpharmacologic treatments for muscle cramps?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;. Data are insufficient to draw any conclusion on the efficacy of calf stretching in reducing the frequency of muscle cramps. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;. None (&lt;strong&gt;Level U&lt;/strong&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question 2: Is quinine effective in the treatment of muscle cramps?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;. On the basis of data from 2 Class I studies, quinine derivatives are effective in reducing the frequency of muscle cramps, although the magnitude of benefit is small. Moreover, these agents are associated with serious though uncommon side effects. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;. Although likely effective (&lt;strong&gt;Level A&lt;/strong&gt;), the use of quinine derivatives for treatment of muscle cramps should be avoided for routine treatment of cramps. These agents should only be considered when cramps are very disabling, no other agents relieve symptoms, and there is careful monitoring of side effects. They should only be used after informing the patient of the potentially serious side effects. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Question 3: Are there any other pharmacologic treatments effective for the treatment of muscle cramps?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;. On the basis of single Class II studies, naftidrofuryl, vitamin B complex, and diltiazem are possibly effective in the treatment of muscle cramps. Naftidrofuryl is currently not available in the United States. Data regarding the use of magnesium preparations (2 Class II studies) and gabapentin (1 study in amyotrophic lateral sclerosis [ALS]) show that these agents are probably not effective in the treatment of muscle cramps. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;. Naftidrofuryl, diltiazem, and vitamin B complex may be considered for the treatment of muscle cramps (&lt;strong&gt;Level C&lt;/strong&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification of Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level A&lt;/strong&gt; = Established as effective, ineffective or harmful (or established as useful/predictive or not useful/predictive) for the given condition in the specified population. (Level A rating requires at least two consistent Class I studies.)*&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level B&lt;/strong&gt; = Probably effective, ineffective or harmful (or probably useful/predictive or not useful/predictive) for the given condition in the specified population. (Level B rating requires at least one Class I study or two consistent Class II studies.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level C&lt;/strong&gt; = Possibly effective, ineffective or harmful (or possibly useful/predictive or not useful/predictive) for the given condition in the specified population. (Level C rating requires at least one Class II study or two consistent Class III studies.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level U&lt;/strong&gt; = Data inadequate or conflicting; given current knowledge, treatment (test, predictor) is unproven.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*In exceptional cases, one convincing Class I study may suffice for an &quot;A&quot; recommendation if 1) all criteria are met, 2) the magnitude of effect is large (relative rate improved outcome &amp;gt;5 and the lower limit of the confidence interval is &amp;gt;2).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification of Evidence for Studies of Therapeutic Intervention&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class I&lt;/strong&gt; = A randomized, controlled clinical trial of the intervention of interest with masked or objective outcome assessment, in a representative population. Relevant baseline characteristics are presented and substantially equivalent among treatment groups or there is appropriate statistical adjustment for differences. The following are also required:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: lower-alpha;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Concealed allocation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Primary outcome(s) clearly defined &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Exclusion/inclusion criteria clearly defined &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adequate accounting for drop-outs (with at least 80% of enrolled subjects completing the study) and cross-overs with numbers sufficiently low to have minimal potential for bias &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;For non-inferiority or equivalence trials claiming to prove efficacy for one or both drugs, the following are also required*:&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The authors explicitly state the clinically meaningful difference to be excluded by defining the threshold for equivalence or non-inferiority. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The standard treatment used in the study is substantially similar to that used in previous studies establishing efficacy of the standard treatment. (e.g., for a drug, the mode of administration, dose and dosage adjustments are similar to those previously shown to be effective). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The inclusion and exclusion criteria for patient selection and the outcomes of patients on the standard treatment are comparable to those of previous studies establishing efficacy of the standard treatment. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The interpretation of the results of the study is based upon a per protocol analysis that takes into account dropouts or crossovers. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class II&lt;/strong&gt; = A randomized controlled clinical trial of the intervention of interest in a representative population with masked or objective outcome assessment that lacks one criteria a&amp;ndash;e above or a prospective matched cohort study with masked or objective outcome assessment in a representative population that meets b&amp;ndash;e above. Relevant baseline characteristics are presented and substantially equivalent among treatment groups or there is appropriate statistical adjustment for differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class III&lt;/strong&gt; = All other controlled trials (including well-defined natural history controls or patients serving as own controls) in a representative population, where outcome is independently assessed, or independently derived by objective outcome measurement.**&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class IV&lt;/strong&gt; = Studies not meeting Class I, II, or III criteria including consensus or expert opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Note that numbers 1-3 in Class Ie are required for Class II in equivalence trials. If any one of the three is missing, the class is automatically downgraded to Class III.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;**Objective outcome measurement: an outcome measure that is unlikely to be affected by an observer's (patient, treating physician, investigator) expectation or bias (e.g., blood tests, administrative outcome data).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None provided&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Idiopathic muscle cramps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Assessment of Therapeutic Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Treatment" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Family Practice" />
      <FieldValue Value="Geriatrics" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Neurology" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Pharmacists" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Assistants" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physicians" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To provide evidence-based recommendations for symptomatic treatment of idiopathic muscle cramps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients with idiopathic muscle cramps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Quinine derivatives &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Naftidrofuryl &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Diltiazem &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Vitamin B complex &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Calf stretching was considered but not recommended.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Incidence of painful muscle cramps &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Efficacy of therapy &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adverse effects of therapy &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Primary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Secondary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;2010 Guideline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The main search strategy was a comprehensive search of MEDLINE and EMBASE from 1950 to May 31, 2008, using the search term &quot;muscle cramp&quot; limited to keywords &quot;therapy,&quot; &quot;drug therapy,&quot; and &quot;prevention and control,&quot; which yielded 558 results in 4 languages (including French, German, Spanish, and English). Additional articles were identified by cross referencing bibliographies from meta-analyses, review articles, and case reports identified in the initial search, which yielded 5 additional articles. &quot;Muscle cramp&quot; was defined as a sustained, generally painful, involuntary contraction of a muscle or muscle group. &quot;Cramps&quot; alone was not used as a search term due to excessive articles on gynecologic and gastrointestinal cramps.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The abstracts and titles from the 563 articles identified were reviewed, and a study was included if it was a prospective clinical trial with effect on muscle cramps as a primary or secondary outcome. Exclusion criteria were 1) review articles, 2) meta-analyses, 3) case reports or case series that did not involve a treatment, 4) phenomena not consistent with muscle cramps, such as muscle spasms, dystonia, or muscle pains, 5) pregnancy-induced cramps, 6) medical conditions such as hemodialysis and cirrhosis, and 7) cramps due to extreme physiologic stress such as excessive exercise, heat, or dehydration. Cramps secondary to medical conditions were excluded from this analysis because the mechanisms underlying the formation of cramps and often the treatment directed to correct them are distinct from the routine treatment of muscle cramps, and most treatment trials assessing idiopathic cramps also excluded these conditions. Muscle cramps due to myopathies were also excluded due to the distinct underlying mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A total of 50 potential studies were identified for full review. Full review of the articles led to further exclusion of 26 articles that were review articles, letters, or repeat publications of the same clinical trials. The remaining 24 articles were chosen for inclusion in the final review, including one article dealing with nonpharmacologic therapy, 5 open-label pharmacologic trials, and 18 randomized pharmacologic trials.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;2013 Reaffirmation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Medline and Cochrane databases were searched from 2010 February 23 to 2013 July 13, using the following terms: &quot;muscle cramp&quot; limited to keywords &quot;therapy,&quot; &quot;drug therapy,&quot; and &quot;prevention and control.&quot; Exclusion criteria were 1) review articles, 2) meta-analyses, 3) case reports or case series that did not involve a treatment, 4) phenomena not consistent with muscle cramps, such as muscle spasms, dystonia, or muscle pains, 5) pregnancy-induced cramps, 6) medical conditions such as hemodialysis and cirrhosis, and 7) cramps due to extreme physiologic stress such as excessive exercise, heat, or dehydration. A study was included if it was a prospective clinical trial with effect on muscle cramps as a primary or secondary outcome.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;2016 Reaffirmation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Medline database was searched from January 2013 to July 2016 using the following search terms: (muscle cramps) AND treatment. Inclusion criteria were RCTs, humans only, relevant to clinical questions; exclusion criteria used to screen search results were the same as described in the 2010 published guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;24&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Classification of Evidence for Studies of Therapeutic Intervention&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class I&lt;/strong&gt; = A randomized, controlled clinical trial of the intervention of interest with masked or objective outcome assessment, in a representative population. Relevant baseline characteristics are presented and substantially equivalent among treatment groups or there is appropriate statistical adjustment for differences. The following are also required:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: lower-alpha;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Concealed allocation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Primary outcome(s) clearly defined &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Exclusion/inclusion criteria clearly defined &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adequate accounting for drop-outs (with at least 80% of enrolled subjects completing the study) and cross-overs with numbers sufficiently low to have minimal potential for bias &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;For non-inferiority or equivalence trials claiming to prove efficacy for one or both drugs, the following are also required*:&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The authors explicitly state the clinically meaningful difference to be excluded by defining the threshold for equivalence or non-inferiority. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The standard treatment used in the study is substantially similar to that used in previous studies establishing efficacy of the standard treatment. (e.g., for a drug, the mode of administration, dose and dosage adjustments are similar to those previously shown to be effective). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The inclusion and exclusion criteria for patient selection and the outcomes of patients on the standard treatment are comparable to those of previous studies establishing efficacy of the standard treatment. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;The interpretation of the results of the study is based upon a per protocol analysis that takes into account dropouts or crossovers. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class II&lt;/strong&gt; = A randomized controlled clinical trial of the intervention of interest in a representative population with masked or objective outcome assessment that lacks one criteria a&amp;ndash;e above or a prospective matched cohort study with masked or objective outcome assessment in a representative population that meets b&amp;ndash;e above. Relevant baseline characteristics are presented and substantially equivalent among treatment groups or there is appropriate statistical adjustment for differences.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class III&lt;/strong&gt; = All other controlled trials (including well-defined natural history controls or patients serving as own controls) in a representative population, where outcome is independently assessed, or independently derived by objective outcome measurement.**&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Class IV&lt;/strong&gt; = Studies not meeting Class I, II, or III criteria including consensus or expert opinion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Note that numbers 1-3 in Class Ie are required for Class II in equivalence trials. If any one of the three is missing, the class is automatically downgraded to Class III.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;**Objective outcome measurement: an outcome measure that is unlikely to be affected by an observer's (patient, treating physician, investigator) expectation or bias (e.g., blood tests, administrative outcome data).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Review of Published Meta-Analyses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final 24 articles (the source documents) involving symptomatic treatment of cramps were distributed to all 3 panel members for critical analysis and classification. Each member of the panel made an independent determination of class of evidence and a final meeting was called to discuss the articles and resolve differences. Data regarding cohort size, completion rate, inclusion and exclusion criteria, treatment and dosage, design of the study, length of study, primary and secondary outcomes, efficacy, and effect size were extracted from each article and tabulated (table e-1 on the Neurology&amp;reg; Web site at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neurology.org&quot; title=&quot;Neurology Journal Web site&quot;&gt;www.neurology.org&lt;/a&gt;). Each article was classified according to the American Academy of Neurology therapeutic classification of evidence scheme (see the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;2010 Guideline&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recommendations were based on the level of evidence (see the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;2013 Reaffirmation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An author conducted a literature search using the same criteria as presented in the original guideline. Because the guideline recommendations would not changes given the new literature available, the committee voted to reaffirm the guideline, stating that the conclusions and recommendations are still valid.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;2016 Reaffirmation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A Guideline Development, Dissemination, and Implementation (GDDI) Subcommittee member who had expertise in neuromuscular disease conducted a targeted literature search for high quality studies using the same criteria as presented in the original guideline. The GDDI reviewer and the subcommittee reviewed the new evidence and determined that the following three criteria were met: 1. There is no new evidence that would alter conclusions or recommendations in the guideline since the last literature search, 2. Guideline methodology is sound and current methodology is not substantially different, and 3. No significant practice variation relevant to the guideline currently exists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Classification of Recommendations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level A&lt;/strong&gt; = Established as effective, ineffective or harmful (or established as useful/predictive or not useful/predictive) for the given condition in the specified population. (Level A rating requires at least two consistent Class I studies.)*&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level B&lt;/strong&gt; = Probably effective, ineffective or harmful (or probably useful/predictive or not useful/predictive) for the given condition in the specified population. (Level B rating requires at least one Class I study or two consistent Class II studies.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level C&lt;/strong&gt; = Possibly effective, ineffective or harmful (or possibly useful/predictive or not useful/predictive) for the given condition in the specified population. (Level C rating requires at least one Class II study or two consistent Class III studies.)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level U&lt;/strong&gt; = Data inadequate or conflicting; given current knowledge, treatment (test, predictor) is unproven.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*In exceptional cases, one convincing Class I study may suffice for an &quot;A&quot; recommendation if 1) all criteria are met, 2) the magnitude of effect is large (relative rate improved outcome &amp;gt;5 and the lower limit of the confidence interval is &amp;gt;2).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A formal cost analysis was not performed and published cost analyses were not reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="External Peer Review" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology (AAN) reviewed and approved a draft of the article. The draft was next sent to members of the Practice Committee of the AAN for further review and then to Neurology&amp;reg; for peer review. Boards of the AAN reviewed and approved the final version of the article. At each step of the review process, external reviewers' suggestions were explicitly considered. When appropriate, the expert panel made changes to the document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The guideline was approved by the Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee on April 28, 2009, by the Practice Committee on July 1, 2009 and by the AAN Board of Directors November 9, 2009.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The type of supporting evidence is identified and graded for each recommendation (see the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Appropriate choice of a treatment for patients with symptomatic idiopathic muscle cramps&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The reported side effects in case reports and prospective trials using quinine sulfate or derivatives are listed in the table in the original guideline document. The most common serious side effects reported were hematologic abnormalities such as hemolytic uremic syndrome&amp;ndash;thrombotic thrombocytopenia purpura, disseminated intravascular coagulation, and bleeding diathesis. These agents should only be used after informing the patient of the potentially serious side effects. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Treatment with naftidrofuryl included mild gastrointestinal discomfort. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="430" OrdBy="800" Name="Contraindications">
    <Field FieldID="144" OrdBy="805" ID="431" Name="Contraindications" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quinine derivatives should be avoided for routine use in the management of muscle cramps because of the potential for toxicity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This statement is provided as an educational service of the American Academy of Neurology (AAN). It is based on an assessment of current scientific and clinical information. It is not intended to include all possible proper methods of care for a particular neurologic problem or all legitimate criteria for choosing to use a specific procedure. Neither is it intended to exclude any reasonable alternative methodologies. The AAN recognizes that specific patient care decisions are the prerogative of the patient and the physician caring for the patient, based on all of the circumstances involved.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An implementation strategy was not provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="117" OrdBy="1015" ID="437" Name="Implementation Tools" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Foreign Language Translations" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient Resources" />
      <FieldValue Value="Quick Reference Guides/Physician Guides" />
      <FieldValue Value="Resources" />
      <FieldValue Value="Wall Poster" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Safety" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Katzberg HD, Khan AH, So YT. Assessment: symptomatic treatment for muscle cramps (an evidence-based review): report of the Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee of the American Academy of Neurology. Neurology. 2010 Feb 23;74(8):691-6. [36 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=20177124&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2010 Feb 23 (reaffirmed 2016 Jul 16)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="American Academy of Neurology - Medical Specialty Society" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;American Academy of Neurology (AAN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Guideline Authors&lt;/em&gt;: Hans D. Katzberg, MD; Ahmir H. Khan, MD; Yuen T. So, MD, PhD&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Therapeutics and Technology Assessment Subcommittee Members (2007-2009)&lt;/em&gt;: Janis M. Miyasaki, MD, MEd, FAAN (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;); Yuen T. So, MD, PhD (&lt;em&gt;Co-Chair&lt;/em&gt;); Richard M. Camicioli, MD; Vinay Chaudhry, MD, FAAN; Richard M. Dubinsky, MD, MPH, FAAN; Cynthia L. Harden, MD; Cheryl Jaigobin, MD; Irene L. Katzan, MD; Barbara S. Koppel, MD, FAAN; James C. Stevens, MD, FAAN (Ex-Officio); William H. Theodore, MD, FAAN. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Disclosure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dr. Katzberg has received funding for travel from the Muscular Dystrophy Association. Dr. Khan reports no disclosures. Dr. So receives royalties from the publication of Occupational &amp;amp; Environmental Medicine (Appleton &amp;amp; Lange, 2007) and articles published in UpToDate (2007); receives research support from Pfizer Inc, NeurogesX, Inc., and the NIH (NIEHS R01 [Co-I], NIEHS R01 [Co-I], and NINDS R01 [Site PI]); estimates 10% of his clinical effort is spent on EMG; and holds equity in Satoris, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Conflict of Interest&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American Academy of Neurology (AAN) is committed to producing independent, critical and truthful clinical practice guidelines (CPGs). Significant efforts are made to minimize the potential for conflicts of interest to influence the recommendations of this CPG. To the extent possible, the AAN keeps separate those who have a financial stake in the success or failure of the products appraised in the CPGs and the developers of the guidelines. Conflict of interest forms were obtained from all authors and reviewed by an oversight committee prior to project initiation. AAN limits the participation of authors with substantial conflicts of interest. The AAN forbids commercial participation in, or funding of, guideline projects. Drafts of the guideline have been reviewed by at least three AAN committees, a network of neurologists, Neurology&amp;reg; peer reviewers and representatives from related fields. The AAN Guideline Author Conflict of Interest Policy can be viewed at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aan.com&quot; title=&quot;AAN Web site&quot;&gt;www.aan.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="159" OrdBy="1255" ID="453" Name="Guideline Endorser(s)" Type="orglist">
      <FieldValue Value="American Association of Neuromuscular and Electrodiagnostic Medicine - Medical Specialty Society" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American Academy of Neurology (AAN) reaffirmed the currency of the guideline in July 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A list of American Academy of Neurology (AAN) guidelines, along with a link this guideline, is available at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aan.com/Guidelines/&quot; title=&quot;AAN Web site&quot;&gt;AAN Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Print copies: Available from the AAN Member Services Center, (800) 879-1960, or from AAN, 201 Chicago Avenue South, Minneapolis, MN 55415.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Symptomatic treatment for muscle cramps. AAN summary of evidence-based guideline for clinicians. St. Paul (MN): American Academy of Neurology. 2010. 1 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aan.com/Guidelines/Home/GetGuidelineContent/394&quot; title=&quot;AAN Web site&quot;&gt;American Academy of Neurology (AAN) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Assessment: symptomatic treatment for muscle cramps. Poster. St. Paul (MN): American Academy of Neurology. 2010. 1 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aan.com/Guidelines/Home/GetGuidelineContent/406&quot; title=&quot;AAN Web site&quot;&gt;AAN Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AAN guideline development process [online]: Assessment: symptomatic treatment for muscle cramps (an evidence-based review); St. Paul (MN): American Academy of Neurology. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aan.com/Guidelines/Home/Development&quot; title=&quot;AAN Web site&quot;&gt;AAN Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, a Chinese translation of the original guideline document is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neurology.org/cgi/content/full/74/8/691/DC3&quot; title=&quot;Neurology Journal Web site&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Neurology&lt;/em&gt; journal Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Drug treatments for symptoms of muscle cramps. AAN summary of evidence-based guideline for patients and their families. 2010. 2 p. St. Paul (MN): American Academy of Neurology. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aan.com/Guidelines/Home/GetGuidelineContent/395&quot; title=&quot;AAN Web site&quot;&gt;American Academy of Neurology (AAN) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Disclaimer&quot;&gt;Please note: This patient information is intended to provide health professionals with information to share with their patients to help them better understand their health and their diagnosed disorders. By providing access to this patient information, it is not the intention of NGC to provide specific medical advice for particular patients. Rather we urge patients and their representatives to review this material and then to consult with a licensed health professional for evaluation of treatment options suitable for them as well as for diagnosis and answers to their personal medical questions. This patient information has been derived and prepared from a guideline for health care professionals included on NGC by the authors or publishers of that original guideline. The patient information is not reviewed by NGC to establish whether or not it accurately reflects the original guideline's content.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This summary was completed by ECRI Institute on August 30, 2010. The currency of the guideline was reaffirmed by the developer in July 2013 and the summary was updated by ECRI Institute on December 22, 2015. The currency of the guideline was reaffirmed by the developer in July 2016 and the summary was updated by ECRI Institute on January 18, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary is based on the original guideline, which is copyrighted by the American Academy of Neurology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse™ (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>