<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;An international ISHLT/ATS/ERS clinical practice guideline: diagnosis and management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Meyer KC, Raghu G, Verleden GM, Corris PA, Aurora P, Wilson KC, Brozek J, Glanville AR, ISHLT/ATS/ERS BOS Task Force Committee. An international ISHLT/ATS/ERS clinical practice guideline: diagnosis and management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome. Eur Respir J. 2014 Dec;44(6):1479-503. [180 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=25359357&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strength of the recommendations (&lt;strong&gt;strong, &lt;span&gt;conditional&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;) and quality of evidence (&lt;strong&gt;high, moderate, low or very low&lt;/strong&gt;) are defined at the end of the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Risk Factors Associated with the Development of Bronchiolitis Obliterans Syndrome (BOS)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-minimal (Grade &amp;ge;A2) Acute Cellular Rejection and Lymphocytic Bronchiolitis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommendation 1&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For lung transplant recipients who have non-minimal acute cellular rejection (Grade &amp;ge;A2) or lymphocytic bronchiolitis on transbronchial lung biopsy specimens, the Committee suggests augmented immunosuppression with a course of systemic steroids to prevent the development of BOS (&lt;strong&gt;conditional recommendation, very low quality evidence&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values and Preferences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This recommendation places a high value on preventing a life-threatening complication of lung transplantation and a lower value on avoiding short-term adverse effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A typical course of systemic corticosteroids used to augment immunosuppression in adult recipients is intravenous methylprednisolone 1000 mg daily for 3 days (many centres use 10-15 mg&amp;middot;kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; per day for smaller patients).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Minimal (Grade A1) Acute Cellular Rejection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommendation 2&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For lung transplant recipients who have clinically significant minimal acute cellular rejection (Grade A1) on transbronchial lung biopsy specimens, the Committee suggests augmented immunosuppression with a course of systemic steroids to prevent the development of BOS (&lt;strong&gt;conditional recommendation, very low quality evidence&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values and Preferences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This recommendation places a high value on preventing a life-threatening complication of lung transplantation and a lower value on avoiding short-term side-effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Committee members consider Grade A1 acute cellular rejection to be clinically significant if it is associated with clinical findings, such as symptoms (e.g., dyspnoea, fatigue or new-onset cough) or objective measurements (e.g., decline in forced expiratory volume in 1 second [FEV&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;] or oxyhaemoglobin desaturation with ambulation), that suggest the presence of allograft dysfunction. A typical course of systemic steroids used to augment immunosuppression in adult recipients is intravenous methylprednisolone 1000 mg daily for 3 days (many centres use 10&amp;ndash;15 mg&amp;middot;kg&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; per day for smaller patients).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Treatment and Prevention of BOS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term High-Dose Corticosteroids&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommendation 3&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For lung transplant recipients who develop a decline in FEV&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; consistent with the onset of BOS, the Committee suggests that clinicians do not use long-term, high-dose corticosteroids (&lt;strong&gt;conditional recommendation, very low quality evidence&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values and Preferences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This recommendation places a high value on avoiding harmful effects due to ineffective therapies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Committee defines sustained administration of high-dose corticosteroid as &amp;ge;30 mg&amp;middot;day&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; of prednisone or an equivalent formulation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Converting Cyclosporine to Tacrolimus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommendation 4&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For lung transplant recipients who develop BOS while receiving chronic immunosuppression with a regimen that includes cyclosporine, the Committee suggests switching the cyclosporine to tacrolimus (&lt;strong&gt;conditional recommendation, very low quality evidence&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values and Preferences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This recommendation places a higher value on mitigation of lung function decline and a lower value on avoiding nephrotoxicity and hyperglycaemia.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The conversion of cyclosporine to tacrolimus is generally performed by stopping cyclosporine and initiating tacrolimus while transiently increasing maintenance corticosteroid dosing until tacrolimus blood levels are ascertained to have reached the desired target range. The target for therapeutic trough blood levels of tacrolimus is generally considered to range from 5 to 15 ng&amp;middot;mL&lt;sup&gt;-1&lt;/sup&gt; for patients who are &amp;ge;18 years of age once a steady state has been attained.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Azithromycin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommendation 5&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For lung transplant recipients who develop a decline in FEV&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; consistent with the onset of BOS, the Committee suggests a trial of azithromycin (&lt;strong&gt;conditional recommendation, very low quality evidence&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values and Preferences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This recommendation places a high value on preventing lung function deterioration and possibly reducing mortality, and a lower value on avoiding adverse effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Azithromycin is generally administered orally at 250 mg per day for 5 days and then 250 mg three times per week. The Committee defines a trial of azithromycin as treating continuously with azithromycin for a minimum of 3 months. Additionally, it is unclear 1) whether azithromycin should be continued long-term if a beneficial response is observed, or 2) whether it should be discontinued if lung function does not show improvement during follow-up clinical evaluation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anti-reflux Surgery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommendation 6&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For lung transplant recipients who develop a decline in FEV&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt; consistent with the onset of BOS and have confirmed gastro-oesophageal reflux (GOR), the Committee suggests referral to an experienced surgeon to be evaluated for potential fundoplication of the gastro-oesophageal junction (&lt;strong&gt;conditional recommendation, very low quality evidence&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values and Preferences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This recommendation places a high value on reducing the risk of lung function deterioration and possibly mortality, and a lower value on avoiding surgical complications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Nissen fundoplication has been more extensively studied than Toupet fundoplication; however, the Committee has no reason to believe that one is superior to the other and feels that the choice of the surgical technique should remain at the surgeon's discretion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Re-transplantation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recommendation 7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For lung transplant recipients who have developed end-stage BOS refractory to other therapies, the Committee suggests referral to a transplant surgeon to be evaluated for re-transplantation (&lt;strong&gt;conditional recommendation, very low quality evidence&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Values and Preferences&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This recommendation places a high value on avoiding surgical complications (e.g., mortality), recurrent BOS and resource utilisation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Remarks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The selection process for re-transplantation is the same as that used for first-time lung transplantation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Quality of Evidence&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence includes well-designed, well-conducted randomised trials or meta-analyses of randomised trials, without risk of bias, indirectness, imprecision, inconsistency or publication bias. Alternatively, the evidence may include well-designed, well-conducted observational studies with either a very large effect or at least two of the following: a large effect, dose&amp;ndash;response gradient, and/or reverse confounding.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moderate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence includes randomised trials or meta-analyses of randomised trials downgraded because of a serious risk of bias, indirectness, imprecision, inconsistency or publication bias. Alternatively, the evidence may include well-designed, well-conducted observational studies upgraded because of a large effect, dose&amp;ndash;response gradient or reverse confounding.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence includes well-designed, well-conducted observational studies, or randomised trials or meta-analyses of randomised trials downgraded two levels because of very serious risk of bias, indirectness, imprecision, inconsistency or publication bias.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Very low&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence consists of case reports, case series or unsystematic clinical observations (i.e., clinical experience or expert opinion).&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength of Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Strength of Recommendations&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;The committee feels certain that the benefits of the intervention substantially outweigh its risks, burdens and costs.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conditional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;The committee believes, but is uncertain, that the benefits of the intervention substantially outweigh its risks, burdens and costs.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An algorithm titled &quot;Algorithm for Clinical Evaluation of Suspected Bronchiolitis Obliterans Syndrome (BOS)&quot; is provided in the original guideline document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lung transplantation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Management" />
      <FieldValue Value="Prevention" />
      <FieldValue Value="Treatment" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Allergy and Immunology" />
      <FieldValue Value="Critical Care" />
      <FieldValue Value="Family Practice" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Pediatrics" />
      <FieldValue Value="Preventive Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Pulmonary Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Thoracic Surgery" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Assistants" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physicians" />
      <FieldValue Value="Respiratory Care Practitioners" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To revise the definition of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS), discuss the risk factors for the development of BOS, and provide guidance about the management of patients with suspected or confirmed BOS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adults and children who have received lung transplants&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Augmented immunosuppression with a course of systemic steroids to prevent bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Use of long-term high-dose corticosteroids (not recommended) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Switching from cyclosporine to tacrolimus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Trial of azithromycin &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Anti-reflux surgery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Re-transplantation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Risk of developing bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Freedom from BOS &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Lung function (change in forced expiratory volume in 1 second [FEV&lt;sub&gt;1&lt;/sub&gt;]) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mortality &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Survival rates during re-transplantation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Perioperative and postoperative complications and death &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adverse events of treatment &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Primary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Secondary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A comprehensive literature search was performed by a medical librarian. The PubMed interface was used to search MEDLINE for relevant publications (original articles and systematic reviews) from 1980 through to 2009. The search was updated twice in 2012 and in March 2013. The search was limited to humans and English language. The search terms included &quot;lung transplantation&quot;, &quot;bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome&quot; and terms specific to management options considered in the clinical questions. A total of 10,031 manuscripts were identified using the electronic searches. Relevant publications were selected by committee members using pre-specified inclusion criteria, and the bibliographies of selected articles were reviewed to identify additional articles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Committee members used RefWorks to perform the comprehensive review, selected manuscripts that were pertinent to the review, and created folders pertaining to bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) diagnosis, etiology, prevention, and treatment. These manuscripts were then evaluated on a more exhaustive set of criteria per the Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation (GRADE) system for quality of evidence (Committee members were assigned to subcommittees for each specific BOS subtopic and one member was selected to chair the committee and prepare reviews with supporting literature/citations) if they could be used to formulate/support guideline recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A total of 10,031 manuscripts were identified using the electronic searches. Relevant publications were selected by committee members using pre-specified inclusion criteria, and the bibliographies of selected articles were reviewed to identify additional articles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Number of studies pertinent to the questions and used in developing recommendations*:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Does augmented immunosuppression in patients with non-minimal acute cellular rejection (AR) (Grade &amp;ge;2) or lymphocytic bronchiolitis (LB) on transbronchial lung biopsy decrease the subsequent development of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS)? &amp;ndash; 11 studies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Does augmented immunosuppression in patients with non-minimal AR (Grade &amp;ge;2) or LB on transbronchial lung biopsy decrease the subsequent development of BOS? &amp;ndash; 9 studies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Should sustained treatment with high-dose corticosteroids be given to lung transplant recipients who develop BOS? &amp;ndash; 5 studies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Does the replacement of cyclosporine with tacrolimus in the post-transplant immunosuppressive regimen slow the rate of lung function decline in patients who have developed criteria for BOS? &amp;ndash; 10 studies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Should azithromycin be given to patients who develop BOS? &amp;ndash; 11 studies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Should anti-reflux surgery (e.g., fundoplication) be performed for patients who develop BOS and have documented gastro-oesophageal reflux (GOR)? &amp;ndash; 10 studies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Question&lt;/strong&gt;: Should lung re-transplantation be offered to patients who develop end-stage BOS refractory to other therapies? &amp;ndash; 7 studies. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Other literature was also used/cited in discussing existent knowledge/data and drawing conclusions that were not presented as recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Quality of Evidence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Quality of Evidence&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence includes well-designed, well-conducted randomised trials or meta-analyses of randomised trials, without risk of bias, indirectness, imprecision, inconsistency or publication bias. Alternatively, the evidence may include well-designed, well-conducted observational studies with either a very large effect or at least two of the following: a large effect, dose&amp;ndash;response gradient, and/or reverse confounding.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moderate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence includes randomised trials or meta-analyses of randomised trials downgraded because of a serious risk of bias, indirectness, imprecision, inconsistency or publication bias. Alternatively, the evidence may include well-designed, well-conducted observational studies upgraded because of a large effect, dose&amp;ndash;response gradient or reverse confounding.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence includes well-designed, well-conducted observational studies, or randomised trials or meta-analyses of randomised trials downgraded two levels because of very serious risk of bias, indirectness, imprecision, inconsistency or publication bias.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Very low&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;Evidence consists of case reports, case series or unsystematic clinical observations (i.e., clinical experience or expert opinion).&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Review of Published Meta-Analyses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review with Evidence Tables" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Members of the committee were provided with the entire collection of compiled documents and subcommittees were formed to address specific topics. Each subcommittee reviewed, appraised and summarised the relevant evidence. The GRADE (Grading of Recommendation, Assessment, Development and Evaluation) approach was used to appraise the quality of the body of evidence supporting each recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The pragmatic evidence synthesis was primarily qualitative, rather than quantitative (i.e., few data could be pooled via meta-analysis).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The methods used for this guideline are summarised in Table 5 in the original guideline document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Evidence tables summarising the relevant literature for each recommendation are provided in the online supplementary material (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation (ISHLT), American Thoracic Society (ATS) and European Respiratory Society (ERS) sponsored &lt;em&gt;ad hoc&lt;/em&gt; committee held preliminary meetings in April and May of 2008 to begin the process of identifying and prioritising topics to be covered in this guideline. The chairs were approved by the three societies. Panel members were identified as leaders in the field of lung transplantation and were selected from established transplant centres worldwide, by the chairs, to review the existing literature and to answer clinical questions based upon the published evidence or, when such evidence was lacking, to provide guidance based upon the observations in their clinical practice. Each member of the committee was involved in developing the conclusions and recommendations provided by this document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Members of the committee were provided with the entire collection of compiled documents and subcommittees were formed to address specific topics. Each subcommittee reviewed, appraised and summarised the relevant evidence. The Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation (GRADE) approach was used to appraise the quality of the body of evidence supporting each recommendation. Clinical questions related to treatment versus no treatment, one treatment versus an alternative treatment, or which populations to treat were answered with recommendations that were formulated and graded using the GRADE approach (see the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence&quot; and &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations&quot; fields). Disagreements were resolved by discussion and consensus. The final recommendations and grades were reviewed by the entire committee and approved in September 2013. In contrast to the systematically developed recommendations, other committee conclusions were based upon the literature appraisal and committee deliberations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A strong recommendation was made if the committee felt confident of the balance between desirable and undesirable consequences. A conditional recommendation was made if the committee felt less confident of the balance between desirable and undesirable consequences. Factors that influence the strength of recommendations include the estimates of effect for desirable and undesirable outcomes of interest, confidence in these estimates of effects, estimates of values and preferences, and resource use. In any case the appropriate course of action depends upon the clinical context. The committees' judgments about the underlying values and preferences of well-informed patients were based upon the committee members' clinical experience. Evidence tables summarising the relevant literature for each recommendation are provided in the online supplementary material (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The committee identified very few experimental studies of the management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS). Available data are very limited owing to the small number of subjects. Thus, most of the recommendations are based upon observational studies with or without a control group and the clinical experience of the committee members (i.e., unsystematic clinical observations from their clinical practices).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Strength of Recommendations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Strength of Recommendations&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;The committee feels certain that the benefits of the intervention substantially outweigh its risks, burdens and costs.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conditional&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td&gt;The committee believes, but is uncertain, that the benefits of the intervention substantially outweigh its risks, burdens and costs.&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A formal cost analysis was not performed and published cost analyses were not reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The final recommendations and grades were reviewed by the entire Task Force Committee and approved in September 2013.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The type of supporting evidence is identified and graded for each recommendation (see the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Most of the recommendations are based upon observational studies with or without a control group and the clinical experience of the committee members (i.e., unsystematic clinical observations from their clinical practices).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This guideline is intended to enhance the understanding of the diagnosis and management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) by transplant physicians and other clinicians, and to assist them in the making appropriate clinical decisions when evaluating patients in whom a diagnosis of BOS is suspected. This guideline can be used worldwide to help standardise the management of BOS. It is hoped that this guideline will provoke and facilitate future clinical studies in lung transplant recipients who develop delayed loss of allograft function.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;When deciding whether or not augmented immunosuppression is warranted, the likelihood of preventing bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) must be balanced against the harms of the increased immunosuppression. This balance will vary depending upon the regimen chosen; however, a short course of systemic steroids is the most common regimen selected. The best evidence regarding the potential adverse effects of a short course of systemic steroids is indirect, extrapolated from randomised trials conducted in patients having an exacerbation of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD). Such trials have found that short courses of systemic steroids increase the incidence of adverse effects, particularly hyperglycaemia and weight gain. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sustained high-dose corticosteroids increase the incidence of osteoporotic fractures, cataracts and dyspepsia. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The most common adverse effects of azithromycin are nausea, diarrhoea, dyspepsia and colitis, occurring in fewer than 5% of patients. A meta-analysis of 12 randomised trials with 1406 patients who received azithromycin to treat an acute lower respiratory tract infection found that 244 (17.9%) out of 1363 patients developed an adverse event. Most of the adverse events were minor nausea and diarrhoea. In an observational study that looked at more than one million instances of taking azithromycin, patients who took azithromycin were more likely to suffer a fatal cardiac arrhythmia than those who did not take an antibiotic (risk ratio 2.85, 95% confidence interval [CI] 1.13&amp;ndash;7.24). The absolute risk of a fatal cardiac arrhythmia during azithromycin therapy was small (1.1 cases per 1000 person-years) and the risk was not increased compared with patients who took an alternative antibiotic (risk ratio 0.93, 95% CI 0.56&amp;ndash;1.55). These findings were supported by another study conducted by the maker of azithromycin. There is also evidence from a randomised trial that patients with COPD who are treated with chronic azithromycin therapy are more likely to experience a decrement in hearing and colonisation with azithromycin-resistant organisms. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Several studies reported a complication rate of less than 5% of patients after anti-reflux surgery, a perioperative mortality rate of less than 1%, and post-operative dysphagia in 6% to 14% of patients. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Most of the case series that described the effects of converting cyclosporine to tacrolimus in lung transplant patients with BOS did not mention adverse effects; however, those that evaluated nephrotoxicity or hyperglycaemia reported a frequent rise in the serum creatinine and glucose levels. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The safety of re-transplantation has not been well studied. In one study, there were 39 (10%) deaths within 180 days among the 389 patients who underwent re-transplantation. The causes of death were infection, respiratory failure and multi-organ system failure. Patients undergoing re-transplantation had an increased risk for death after the procedure compared with patients who underwent primary transplantation. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original guideline document for additional information on treatment safety.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation (ISHLT)/American Thoracic Society (ATS)/European Respiratory Society (ERS) guidelines about the management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome (BOS) are not intended to impose a standard of care. They provide the basis for rational decisions in the management of patients with suspected or confirmed BOS. Clinicians, patients, third-party payers, institutional review committees, other stakeholders or the courts should never view these recommendations as dictates. No guidelines and recommendations can take into account all of the often compelling, unique individual clinical circumstances. Therefore, no one charged with evaluating clinicians' actions should attempt to apply the recommendations from these guidelines by rote or in a blanket fashion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Statements about the underlying values and preferences as well as the qualifying remarks accompanying each recommendation are integral parts and serve to facilitate more accurate interpretation. They should never be omitted when quoting or translating recommendations from these guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An implementation strategy was not provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="117" OrdBy="1015" ID="437" Name="Implementation Tools" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Clinical Algorithm" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
      <FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Meyer KC, Raghu G, Verleden GM, Corris PA, Aurora P, Wilson KC, Brozek J, Glanville AR, ISHLT/ATS/ERS BOS Task Force Committee. An international ISHLT/ATS/ERS clinical practice guideline: diagnosis and management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome. Eur Respir J. 2014 Dec;44(6):1479-503. [180 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=25359357&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2014 Dec" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="American Thoracic Society - Medical Specialty Society" />
      <FieldValue Value="European Respiratory Society - Professional Association" />
      <FieldValue Value="International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation - Professional Association" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation (ISHLT)/American Thoracic Society (ATS)/European Respiratory Society (ERS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;ISHLT/ATS/ERS BOS Task Force Committee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Task Force Committee Chair&lt;/em&gt;: Keith C. Meyer, School of Medicine and Public Health, University of Wisconsin-Madison, Madison, WI, USA&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Task Force Committee Co-Chairs&lt;/em&gt;: Ganesh Raghu, School of Medicine, University of Washington, Seattle, WA, USA; Geert M. Verleden, University of Leuven, Leuven, Belgium; Paul A. Corris, Freeman Hospital, Newcastle upon Tyne, UK; Allan R. Glanville, The Lung Transplant Unit, St Vincents Hospital, Sydney, Australia; Paul Aurora, Great Ormond Street Hospital for Children, London, UK; Jim J. J. Egan, Mater Misericordiae University Hospital, Dublin, Ireland&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Task Force Committee Members&lt;/em&gt;: Selim Arcasoy, Columbia University, New York, NY, USA; Robert M. Aris, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, NC, USA; Robin K. Avery, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA; John Belperio, University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA, USA; Juergen Behr, Ruhr University Bochum, Bochum, Germany; Sangeeta Bhorade, Northwestern University, Chicago, IL, USA; Annette Boehler, University of Zurich, Zurich, Switzerland; Cecilia Chaparro, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Jason D. Christie, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Lieven J. Dupont, Katholieke Universiteit Leuven, Leuven, Belgium; Marc Estenne, Hospital Erasme, Brussels, Belgium; Andrew J. Fisher, University of Newcastle, Newcastle, UK; Edward R. Garrity, Jr, University of Chicago, Chicago, IL, USA; Denis Hadjiliadis, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Marshall I. Hertz, University of Minnesota, Minneapolis, MN, USA; Shahid Husain, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Martin Iversen, Rigshospitalet, Copenhagen, Denmark; Shaf Keshavjee, University of Toronto, Toronto, ON, Canada; Vibha N. Lama, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA; Deborah J. Levine, University of Texas San Antonio, San Antonio, TX, USA; Stephanie M. Levine, University of Texas San Antonio, San Antonio, TX, USA; James C. Lee, University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, USA; Gilbert Massard, University of Strasbourg, Strasbourg, France; Atul C. Mehta, Cleveland Clinic, Cleveland, OH, USA; Steven D. Nathan, Inova Fairfax Hospital, Falls Church, VA, USA; Jonathan B. Orens, Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, MD, USA; Scott M. Palmer, Duke University, Durham, NC, USA; Greg I. Snell, Alfred Hospital, Melbourne, Australia; Marc Stern, H&amp;ocirc;pital Foch Suresnes, Paris, France; Sean M. Studer, New York University, Woodhull Medical Center, New York, NY, USA; Stuart C. Sweet, Washington University, St. Louis, MO, USA; Henry D. Tazelaar, Mayo Clinic, Scottsdale, AZ, USA; Timothy P. Whelan, Medical University of South Carolina, Charleston, SC, USA; David S. Wilkes, Indiana University School of Medicine, Indianapolis, IN, USA; Trevor J. Williams, University of Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia; Martin R. Zamora, University of Colorado, Denver, CO, USA&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methodologists&lt;/em&gt;: Jan Brozek, McMaster University, Hamilton, ON, Canada, and Kevin C. Wilson, Boston University Medical Center, Boston, MA, USA&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All members of the committee disclosed potential conflicts of interest, which were vetted according to the policies of the International Society for Heart and Lung Transplantation (ISHLT), American Thoracic Society (ATS) and European Respiratory Society (ERS). Disclosures can be found alongside the online version of this article at &lt;a href=&quot;http://erj.ersjournals.com/content/44/6/1479/suppl/DC1&quot; title=&quot;European Respiratory Journal Web site&quot;&gt;erj.ersjournals.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electronic copies: Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://erj.ersjournals.com/content/44/6/1479.full.pdf+html&quot; title=&quot;European Respiratory Journal Web site&quot;&gt;European Respiratory Journal Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Diagnosis and management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome: an international ISHLT/ATS/ERS clinical practice guideline. Online supplement. 44 p. Electronic copies: Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://erj.ersjournals.com/content/suppl/2014/10/27/09031936.00107514.DC2/BOS_Guideline_Online_SupplementaryMaterial.pdf&quot; title=&quot;European Respiratory Journal Web site&quot;&gt;European Respiratory Journal Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;An international ISHLT/ATS/ERS clinical practice guideline: diagnosis and management of bronchiolitis obliterans syndrome. Evidence tables. 45 p. Electronic copies: Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://erj.ersjournals.com/content/suppl/2014/10/27/09031936.00107514.DC2/BOS_Guideline_Manuscript-Evidence_Tables_for_On-line_Supplement-May_2014.pdf&quot; title=&quot;European Respiratory Journal Web site&quot;&gt;European Respiratory Journal Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None available&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on July 3, 2015. The information was verified by the guideline developer on July 28, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary is based on the original guideline, which is subject to the guideline developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>