<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Clinical practice guideline on perioperative care in major abdominal surgery.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Work Group of the Clinical Practice Guidelines on Perioperative Care in Major Abdominal Surgery. Clinical practice guideline on perioperative care in major abdominal surgery. Madrid (Spain): Aragon Institute for Health Sciences; 2016. 116 p. [131 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="705" OrdBy="150" Name="NEATS Assessment">
    <Field FieldID="183" OrdBy="10" ID="706" Name="Disclosure of Guideline Funding Source" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Yes" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="184" OrdBy="20" ID="707" Name="Disclosure and Management of Financial Conflict of Interests" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="4" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="185" OrdBy="30" ID="708" Name="Guideline Development Group Composition: Multidisciplinary Group" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Yes" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="186" OrdBy="40" ID="709" Name="Guideline Development Group Composition: Methodologist Involvement" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="Yes" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="187" OrdBy="50" ID="710" Name="Guideline Development Group Composition: Patient and Public Perspectives" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="4" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="188" OrdBy="60" ID="711" Name="Use of a Systematic Review of Evidence: Search Strategy" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="5" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="189" OrdBy="70" ID="712" Name="Use of a Systematic Review of Evidence: Study Selection" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="3" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="190" OrdBy="80" ID="713" Name="Use of a Systematic Review of Evidence: Synthesis of Evidence" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="5" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="191" OrdBy="90" ID="714" Name="Evidence Foundations for and Rating Strength of Recommendations: Grading the Quality or Strength of Evidence" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="3" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="192" OrdBy="100" ID="715" Name="Evidence Foundations for and Rating Strength of Recommendations: Benefits and Harms of Recommendations" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="5" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="193" OrdBy="110" ID="716" Name="Evidence Foundations for and Rating Strength of Recommendations: Evidence Summary Supporting Recommendations" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="5" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="194" OrdBy="120" ID="717" Name="Evidence Foundations for and Rating Strength of Recommendations: Rating the Strength of Recommendations" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="4" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="195" OrdBy="130" ID="718" Name="Specific and Unambiguous Articulation of Recommendations" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="5" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="196" OrdBy="140" ID="719" Name="External Review" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="4" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="197" OrdBy="150" ID="720" Name="Updating" Type="picklist-one">
      <FieldValue Value="5" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Levels of evidence (&lt;strong&gt;1++ to 4&lt;/strong&gt;) and grades of recommendation (&lt;strong&gt;A to D, GCP&lt;/strong&gt;) are defined at the end of the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Preoperative Measures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information for Patients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who are going to undergo abdominal surgery, does information on the process (via clinic) help reduce the length of hospital stays?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCP&lt;/strong&gt; - Oral and written information should be given to patients who are going to undergo major abdominal surgery, describing what will take place during the entire hospital stay, resolving any doubts and making the patient a participant in the surgical process. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCP&lt;/strong&gt; - It is recommended that the information that is communicated to the patient who is going to undergo major abdominal surgery be agreed upon previously by a multi-disciplinary team to promote a comprehensive understanding of the surgical process. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nutritional Screening&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who are going to undergo abdominal surgery, does the study of the state of the patient's nutritional state reduce postoperative complications (morbi-mortality)?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; - Nutritional screening of all patients who are going to undergo major abdominal surgery is recommended. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCP&lt;/strong&gt; - The assessment of the patient's nutritional state should be done during the preoperative visit to allow sufficient time for the nutritional support teams present in each centre to take the necessary measures based on the results of the assessment. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCP&lt;/strong&gt; - It is recommended that nutritional treatment be initiated during the preoperative period in all patients identified as being at risk of malnutrition during the nutritional screening. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Carbohydrate Drinks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who are going to undergo elective major abdominal surgery, does the administration of carbohydrate drinks (two hours before surgery), versus not administering anything, reduce postoperative complications? Does it shorten hospital stays? &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - In non-diabetic patients who are going to undergo elective major abdominal surgery, the administration of 200 to 400 mL of a carbohydrate drink that contains at least 50 g of glucose, up to 2 hours prior to the surgical procedure, is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - In non-diabetic patients who are going to undergo elective major abdominal surgery, it must be taken into account that the administration, up to 2 hours prior to surgery, of clear carbohydrate liquids is safe, not associated with any harmful effects for patients, such as vomiting or aspiration pneumonitis. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anaesthetic Premedication&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who are going to undergo elective major abdominal surgery, is there any evidence to support that not giving preanaesthetic medication can reduce or prevent postoperative ileus?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - The use of intermediate or long-acting sedative and/or anxiolytic premedication in patients who undergo major abdominal surgery is not recommended. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCP&lt;/strong&gt; - In cases in which the administration of anxiolytic premedication is deemed necessary, short-acting benzodiazepines (BDZs) are recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Intraoperative Measures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhanced Recovery After Abdominal Surgery (ERAS) and Laparoscopic Surgery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who undergo elective major abdominal surgery, do the following interventions reduce morbi-mortality and hospital stays when compared with the use of laparoscopy and conventional perioperative care?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laparoscopy + ERAS&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Laparotomy + ERAS&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - In patients who are going to undergo elective colorectal surgery, the laparoscopic approach is recommended, in combination with the application of an intensified abdominal surgery recovery program. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Perioperative Measures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluid Therapy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who undergo elective major abdominal surgery, does the use of a goal-directed fluid therapy algorithm, versus restrictive fluid therapy, reduce postoperative complications? Does it shorten postoperative ileus? Does it shorten hospital stays?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; - Colorectal surgery that falls within the scope of a program of enhanced recovery after abdominal surgery (ERAS) should include a personalized fluid therapy plan for each patient. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GCP&lt;/strong&gt; - Abdominal surgery that falls within the scope of an ERAS program should include a personalized fluid therapy plan for each patient. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - In patients who undergo colorectal surgery, the use of a haemodynamic goal-directed fluid therapy algorithm is suggested when the necessary human and technical resources are available. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - In patients with low surgical risk (American Society of Anesthesiologists [ASA] I or II) who undergo colorectal surgery within the scope of an ERAS program, evaluate the possibility of applying an intraoperative fluid handling strategy with a balance close to zero. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analgesia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who undergo elective major abdominal surgery, is transversus abdominis plane (TAP) block more effective and safer than epidural analgesia?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scientific evidence is insufficient to support a recommendation in favour of or against the use of TAP block for postoperative analgesia in major abdominal surgery. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - If the TAP technique is used for postoperative analgesia, it should be applied via catheter with continuous perfusion. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Postoperative Measures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Reinitiation of Oral Feeding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who undergo elective major abdominal surgery, does the early administration of oral nutrition versus not administering anything shorten postoperative ileus?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; - In patients who have undergone colorectal surgery, surgery of the small intestine, or gynaecological abdominal surgery, it is recommended that oral ingestion of liquids and solids begin as soon as possible, based on the tolerance of the patient, preferably within the first 24 hours after the surgical procedure, with the possibility of resuming oral feeding starting 4 hours after surgery. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Mobilization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In patients who undergo elective major abdominal surgery, does early mobilization (getting out of bed within the first 6 hours) versus remaining in bed shorten postoperative ileus?&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt; - Implement a plan of perioperative care that promotes early and progressive mobilization of the patient, getting the patient out of bed on the same day of the surgery, and starting to walk within the first 24 hours following the surgery. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Levels of Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Levels of Evidence for Intervention Studies&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1++&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High-quality meta-analyses, systematic reviews of clinical trials or high-quality clinical trials with very low risk of bias&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Well-conducted meta-analyses, systematic reviews of clinical trials, or well-conducted clinical trials with little risk of bias&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Meta-analyses, systematic reviews of clinical trials or clinical trials with a high risk of bias&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2++&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High-quality systematic reviews of case-control or cohort studies. High-quality case-control or cohort studies with a very low risk of confounding or bias and a high probability that the relationship is causal&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High-quality case-control or cohort studies with a very low risk of confounding or bias and a high probability that the relationship is causal&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Cohort or case-control studies with high risk of bias and a significant risk that the relationship is not causal&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Non-analytic studies, such as case reports and case series&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Expert opinion&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies classified as 1- and 2- must not be used for making recommendations due to their high potential for bias.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SIGN Grades of Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Grades of Recommendation for Intervention Studies&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;At least one meta-analysis, systematic review or clinical trial rated as 1++ and directly applicable to the target population of the guide; or a body of evidence consisting of studies rated as 1+ and showing overall consistency of results&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;A body of evidence consisting of studies rated as 2++, directly applicable to the target population of the guide and showing overall consistency of results; or evidence extrapolated from studies rated as 1++ or 1+&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;A body of evidence consisting of studies rated as 2+ directly applicable to the target population of the guide and showing overall consistency of results; or evidence extrapolated from studies rated as 2++&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Evidence levels 3 or 4; or evidence extrapolated from studies rated as 2+&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good Clinical Practice (GCP)*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Recommended practice based on clinical experience and consensus of the editorial team&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Sometimes the development group wishes to highlight an important practical aspect for which there is probably no supporting evidence. In general, these cases are related to an aspect of treatment generally accepted to be good clinical practice and that would not normally be questioned by anyone. These aspects are evaluated as a point of good clinical practice. These messages are not an alternative to the recommendations based on evidence, but should be considered only when there is no other way of highlighting that aspect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None provided&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pathological intra-abdominal processes that require non-urgent (elective) major surgery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Management" />
      <FieldValue Value="Rehabilitation" />
      <FieldValue Value="Treatment" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Anesthesiology" />
      <FieldValue Value="Colon and Rectal Surgery" />
      <FieldValue Value="Gastroenterology" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Obstetrics and Gynecology" />
      <FieldValue Value="Oncology" />
      <FieldValue Value="Surgery" />
      <FieldValue Value="Urology" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Dietitians" />
      <FieldValue Value="Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patients" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Assistants" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physicians" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To serve as an instrument to improve the care of patients who undergo an elective major surgical procedure with abdominal involvement&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This indication includes some of the following procedures: colorectal surgery, gastrectomy, gastric bypass, hysterectomy, prostatectomy, cystectomy, other oncological, gynaecological, and urological surgery, etc. In this sense, the guidelines cover patients from different surgical specializations, such as general surgery, urological, and gynaecological surgery. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All patients older than 18 years of age with pathological intra-abdominal processes that require non-urgent (elective) major surgery&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The scope of this clinical practice guideline (CPG) does not cover emergency surgery, outpatient surgery, and vascular surgery.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Oral and written information for patients &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Nutritional screening &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Nutritional treatment &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Carbohydrate drinks &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Anaesthetic premedication (short-acting benzodiazepines) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Laparoscopic surgery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Enhanced recovery after abdominal surgery &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Personalized fluid therapy &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Use of a haemodynamic goal-directed fluid therapy algorithm &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Intraoperative fluid handling strategy &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Analgesia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Early reinitiation of oral feeding &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Early mobilization &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The following was considered but not recommended: Intermediate or long-acting sedative and/or anxiolytic premedication.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Length of hospital stay &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Postoperative complications &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Morbidity &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mortality &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Postoperative ileus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Primary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Secondary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Unpublished Data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The principal stages involved in the preparation process are described below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Preparation of the clinical questions followed the PICO format (Patient/Intervention/Comparison/Outcome). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Bibliography search, with de novo preparation of strategies for all questions. The sources consulted were MEDLINE (access via PubMed), EMBASE (Elsevier.com), Centre for Reviews and Dissemination (CRD) Databases, The Cochrane Library, &amp;Iacute;ndice Bibliogr&amp;aacute;fico Espa&amp;ntilde;ol en Ciencias de la Salud (IBECs), and Literatura Latinoamericana y del Caribe en Ciencias de la Salud (LILACs). The searches were limited to the types of studies that were most suitable based on the characteristics of the question and the languages of Spanish, French, and English. The search period covered from 2000 to 2014, through the months between May and July. Also, automatic email alerts were configured for new articles added to MEDLINE, EMBASE and The Cochrane Library after July 2014. A reverse search was done in the references of the articles identified and included in the guidelines. A non-systematic search of grey literature was also done. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Initially, the studies that were returned were screened by title and abstract. In a second screening, the discarded studies were recorded and the causes for exclusion were specified. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The methodology used to prepare this CPG is included in the &lt;em&gt;Methodology Manual for Drafting CPGs in the National Health System (NHS)&lt;/em&gt; (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field). &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the Methodological Material document (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field) for a breakdown of the studies identified and included for each clinical question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Levels of Evidence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Levels of Evidence for Intervention Studies&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1++&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High-quality meta-analyses, systematic reviews of clinical trials or high-quality clinical trials with very low risk of bias&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Well-conducted meta-analyses, systematic reviews of clinical trials, or well-conducted clinical trials with little risk of bias&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Meta-analyses, systematic reviews of clinical trials or clinical trials with a high risk of bias&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2++&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High-quality systematic reviews of case-control or cohort studies. High-quality case-control or cohort studies with a very low risk of confounding or bias and a high probability that the relationship is causal&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2+&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High-quality case-control or cohort studies with a very low risk of confounding or bias and a high probability that the relationship is causal&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2-&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Cohort or case-control studies with high risk of bias and a significant risk that the relationship is not causal&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Non-analytic studies, such as case reports and case series&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Expert opinion&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Studies classified as 1- and 2- must not be used for making recommendations due to their high potential for bias.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Review of Published Meta-Analyses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review with Evidence Tables" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The principal stages involved in the preparation process are described below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Evaluation of the quality of the studies and summary of the evidence for each question using the critical reading tool of the Agency for Healthcare Technology Assessment of the Basque Country (OSTEBA). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The methodology used to prepare this clinical practice guideline (CPG) is included in the &lt;em&gt;Methodology Manual for Drafting CPGs in the National Health System (NHS)&lt;/em&gt; (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The principal stages involved in the preparation process are described below:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Creation of a guideline working group made up of 11 healthcare professionals from different disciplines in the area of hospital care, from different regions and different specializations (general surgery, nursing, anaesthesiology, endocrinology and nutrition, urology) and 2 specialists in methodology from the Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon (IACS). To prepare the material aimed at patients, family members, and caregivers, the Work Group was assisted by a patient who had undergone major abdominal surgery (MAS) and had participated in an enhanced recovery after abdominal surgery (ERAS) program. Also, the information aimed at patients, family members, and caregivers was revised by three non-medical persons to ensure that it was suitable and understandable. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Formulation of recommendations based on the &quot;formal evaluation&quot; or &quot;justified opinion&quot; of the Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN). The classification of the evidence and the grading of the recommendations were done using the system proposed by SIGN. In addition to the volume and quality of the evidence, the guideline working group (GWG) had to consider the applicability of the results found, the concordance of the results, and the relevance of their application to the National Health System, or their clinical impact. Recommendations that were controversial or that lacked evidence were resolved by consensus in two meetings of the working group. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The methodology used to prepare this CPG is included in the &lt;em&gt;Methodology Manual for Drafting CPGs in the National Health System (NHS)&lt;/em&gt; (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Grades of Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Scottish Intercollegiate Guidelines Network (SIGN) Grades of Recommendation for Intervention Studies&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;At least one meta-analysis, systematic review or clinical trial rated as 1++ and directly applicable to the target population of the guide; or a body of evidence consisting of studies rated as 1+ and showing overall consistency of results&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;A body of evidence consisting of studies rated as 2++, directly applicable to the target population of the guide and showing overall consistency of results; or evidence extrapolated from studies rated as 1++ or 1+&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;A body of evidence consisting of studies rated as 2+ directly applicable to the target population of the guide and showing overall consistency of results; or evidence extrapolated from studies rated as 2++&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Evidence levels 3 or 4; or evidence extrapolated from studies rated as 2+&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Good Clinical Practice (GCP)*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Recommended practice based on clinical experience and consensus of the editorial team&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Sometimes the development group wishes to highlight an important practical aspect for which there is probably no supporting evidence. In general, these cases are related to an aspect of treatment generally accepted to be good clinical practice and that would not normally be questioned by anyone. These aspects are evaluated as a point of good clinical practice. These messages are not an alternative to the recommendations based on evidence, but should be considered only when there is no other way of highlighting that aspect.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A formal cost analysis was not performed and published cost analyses were not reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="External Peer Review" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The external reviewers reviewed the first draft of the clinical practice guideline (CPG). The expert collaborators participated in the review of the recommendations. The review resulted in the introduction of minor changes in one recommendation, aimed at improving its feasibility.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The scientific societies involved in the development of these guidelines, represented by members of the working group, expert collaborators, and external reviewers were the Spanish Society of Anaesthesiology, Reanimation, and Pain Therapy (SEDAR), the Spanish Multimodal Rehabilitation Group (GERM), the Spanish Association of Surgeons (AEC), the Spanish Association of Coloproctology (AECP), the Spanish Association of Urology (AEU), the Spanish Association of Surgical Nursing (AEEQ), the Spanish Society of Gynaecology and Obstetrics (SEGO), and the Spanish Society of Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (SENPE).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The methodology used to prepare this CPG is included in the &lt;em&gt;Methodology Manual for Drafting CPGs in the National Health System (NHS)&lt;/em&gt; (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The type of supporting evidence is identified and graded for each recommendation (see the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Improving the quality of care and thus optimizing postoperative recovery and rehabilitation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Unifying the many different interventions related to perioperative care and reducing unjustified variability in clinical practice &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original guideline document for information about the benefits of specific interventions observed in the studies that were reviewed for this guideline.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adverse effects of interventions&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Refer to the original guideline document for information about the harms of specific interventions observed in the studies that were reviewed for this guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="430" OrdBy="800" Name="Contraindications">
    <Field FieldID="144" OrdBy="805" ID="431" Name="Contraindications" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The European Medicines Agency (EMA) recommends avoiding the use of hydroxyethyl starch (HES) in patients with sepsis and renal insufficiency because an increase in renal damage has been demonstrated when they are used in the post-resuscitation phase of critical patients in the intensive care unit (ICU). But in the context of perioperative treatment of surgical patients, there is some uncertainty regarding the long-term safety of HESs. The Guideline Work Group (GWG) does not consider HESs to be contraindicated in the treatment of surgical patients, provided that the precautions for their use are respected, which means that the applicability of the results of these studies is not compromised.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This clinical practice guideline (CPG) is intended as an aid to decision-making in healthcare. The guidelines are not mandatory, nor do they take the place of the clinical judgement of healthcare staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Diffusion and Implementation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The clinical practice guideline (CPG) is a tool to assist professionals and users to make decisions regarding the most appropriate health care. The introduction and implementation of the recommendations in these guidelines in the healthcare sectors in which their application is pertinent is therefore necessary. The following strategies are recommended to do this: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Presentation of the CPG by the healthcare authorities to the communication &lt;span&gt;team&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Presentation of the guidelines to the directorates and deputy directorates of Specialized Care of the different regional health services. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Institutional presentation of the guidelines to the different scientific societies and associations involved. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Collaboration with the scientific societies and associations that participated in the review of the CPG, to promote dissemination. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sending the CPG to the different databases that collect information on CPGs, for evaluation and inclusion. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Free access to the different versions of the CPG at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guiasalud.es&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site&quot;&gt;Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Dissemination and information on the CPG at scientific activities related to enhanced recovery in abdominal surgery, general surgery, and surgery of the digestive tract, anaesthesiology and reanimation, urology, gynaecology, and nursing. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Publication of the guidelines in medical magazines. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Translation of the complete version into English. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the implementation of the recommendations of the guidelines, the methodology included in the &lt;em&gt;Methodological Manual for the Implementation of Clinical Practice Guidelines in the National Health System &lt;/em&gt;is proposed. A multidisciplinary team should be created to assume the coordination and leadership of the process. This team will prepare the planning of the implementation, which should include the diagnosis of the practical situation in regard to the recommendations to be implemented, the analysis of potential barriers and facilitating elements, the design and implementation of intervention strategies, as well as the design of a plan that makes it possible to evaluate the development of the implementation process itself, as well as the degree of adjustment and results of the clinical practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="117" OrdBy="1015" ID="437" Name="Implementation Tools" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Foreign Language Translations" />
      <FieldValue Value="Mobile Device Resources" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient Resources" />
      <FieldValue Value="Quick Reference Guides/Physician Guides" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Work Group of the Clinical Practice Guidelines on Perioperative Care in Major Abdominal Surgery. Clinical practice guideline on perioperative care in major abdominal surgery. Madrid (Spain): Aragon Institute for Health Sciences; 2016. 116 p. [131 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline is not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2016" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Aragon Institute for Health Sciences - State/Local Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" />
      <FieldValue Value="GuiaSalud - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" />
      <FieldValue Value="Ministry of Health (Spain) - National Government Agency [Non-U.S.]" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="123" OrdBy="1230" ID="448" Name="Guideline Developer Comment" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Corporate Collaborators&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Specialist in General Spanish Association of Surgeons (AEC) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Association of Coloproctology (AECP) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Association of Surgical Nursing (AEEQ) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Association of Urology (AEU) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Multimode Rehabilitation Group (GERM) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Society of Anaesthesiology, Reanimation, and Pain Therapy (SEDAR) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Society of Nursing in Surgery (SEECir) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Society of Gynaecology and Obstetrics (SEGO) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Spanish Society for Parenteral and Enteral Nutrition (SENPE) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Members of these societies participated in the authorship, expert collaboration, and external review of the clinical practice guideline (CPG).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This document was produced under the collaboration agreement signed by the Institute of Health Carlos III, an autonomous entity of the Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness, and the Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon (IACS), as part of the development of activities of the Spanish Network of Agencies for Health Technology Assessment and NHS benefits, funded by the Ministry of Health, Social Services and Equality.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Work Group of the Clinical Practice Guidelines on Perioperative Care in Major Abdominal Surgery&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;em&gt;Work Group Members&lt;/em&gt;: Antonio Arroyo Sebasti&amp;aacute;n, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital General Universitario de Elche, Elche; Jos&amp;eacute; Mar&amp;iacute;a Calvo Vecino, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Hospital Universitario Infanta Leonor, Madrid; Rub&amp;eacute;n Casans Franc&amp;eacute;s, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Hospital Cl&amp;iacute;nico Universitario Lozano Blesa, Zaragoza; Emilio del Valle Hern&amp;aacute;ndez, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Maranon, Madrid; Patricia Gav&amp;iacute;n Benavent, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Microbiology and Parasitology, Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon, Zaragoza; Mar&amp;iacute;a Jes&amp;uacute;s Gil Sanz, Doctor of Medicine, Urology Specialist, Hospital Universitario Miguel, Servet, Zaragoza; Juan Ignacio Mart&amp;iacute;n S&amp;aacute;nchez, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Preventive Medicine and Public Health, Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon, Zaragoza; Javier Mart&amp;iacute;nez Ubieto, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Hospital Universitario Miguel Servet, Zaragoza; Carmen Gloria Nogueiras Quintas, Nurse, Hospital Universitario de Fuenlabrada, Fuenlabrada; Mar&amp;iacute;a Julia Oc&amp;oacute;n Bret&amp;oacute;n, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Endocrinology and Nutrition, Hospital Cl&amp;iacute;nico Universitario Lozano Blesa, Zaragoza; Jos&amp;eacute; Manuel Ram&amp;iacute;rez Rodr&amp;iacute;guez, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital Cl&amp;iacute;nico Universitario Lozano Blesa, Zaragoza; Pablo Royo Dachary, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital Cl&amp;iacute;nico Universitario Lozano Blesa, Zaragoza; Jorge Subir&amp;aacute; R&amp;iacute;os, Doctor of Medicine, Urology Specialist, Hospital Cl&amp;iacute;nico Universitario Lozano Blesa, Zaragoza&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Coordination&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Clinical Area&lt;/em&gt;: Jos&amp;eacute; Manuel Ram&amp;iacute;rez Rodr&amp;iacute;guez, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital Cl&amp;iacute;nico Universitario Lozano Blesa, Zaragoza &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Methodology Area&lt;/em&gt;: Patricia Gav&amp;iacute;n Benavent, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Microbiology and Parasitology, Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon, Zaragoza; Juan Ignacio Mart&amp;iacute;n S&amp;aacute;nchez, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Preventive Medicine and Public Health, Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon, Zaragoza &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Collaboration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Documentation&lt;/em&gt;: Mar&amp;iacute;a Pilar Blas Diez, Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon, Zaragoza &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Logistical and Administrative Support&lt;/em&gt;: Mar&amp;iacute;a Esther Garc&amp;iacute;a Pomar, Institute of Health Sciences of Aragon, Zaragoza &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Revision of Information for Patients&lt;/em&gt;: Mar&amp;iacute;a Yamina Fandos Falo, Revision of Information for patients as potential users, Zaragoza; Mar&amp;iacute;a Esther Garc&amp;iacute;a Pomar, Revision of Information for patients as potential users, Zaragoza; Jonathan Gir&amp;aacute;ldez S&amp;aacute;nchez, Revision of Information for patients as potential users, Zaragoza; Jos&amp;eacute; Luis Matute M&amp;iacute;nguez, Revision of Information for patients as users of the National Health System, Patient, Zaragoza &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Expert Collaboration&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Francisco Faus Gaband&amp;eacute;, Nurse, Universidad de Valencia, Valencia; Emilia Victoria Guasch Arevalo, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Hospital Universitario de la Paz, Madrid; Juan Jos&amp;eacute; Hern&amp;aacute;ndez Aguado, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Gynaecology and Obstetrics, Hospital Universitario Infanta Leonor, Madrid; Carmelo Loinaz Segurola, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre, Madrid; Luis Mu&amp;ntilde;oz Alameda, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Fundaci&amp;oacute;n Jim&amp;eacute;nez D&amp;iacute;az, Madrid; Luis Quecedo Guti&amp;eacute;rrez, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Hospital Universitario de la Princesa, Madrid; Manuel Romero Simo, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital General Universitario de Alicante, Alicante; Victor Soria Aledo, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital J.M. Morales Meseguer, Murcia &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;External Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alfredo Abad Gurumeta, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Hospital Universitario de la Paz, Madrid; Cristina de la Cuerda Compes, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Endocrinology and Nutrition, Hospital General Universitario Gregorio Maranon, Madrid; Fernando Gilsanz Rodr&amp;iacute;guez, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in Anaesthesia and Reanimation, Hospital Universitario de la Paz, Madrid; Luis Martos Garcia, Nurse, Hospital Cl&amp;iacute;nico Universitario Virgen de la Arrixaca, Murcia; Carlos Moreno Sanz, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital General La Mancha Centro, Ciudad Real; Alfredo Rodr&amp;iacute;guez Antol&amp;iacute;n, Doctor of Medicine, Urology Specialist, Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre, Madrid; Jos&amp;eacute; Vicente Roig Vila, Doctor of Medicine, Specialist in General Surgery and Surgery of the Digestive Tract, Hospital Nisa 9 de Octubre, Valencia&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All members of the Work Group, as well as those who have participated in the expert collaboration and external review, made the declaration of interest below. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Declaration of Interests&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following members of the preparation group have declared that they have no conflicts of interests: &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Antonio Arroyo Sebasti&amp;aacute;n, Jos&amp;eacute; Mar&amp;iacute;a Calvo Vecino, Patricia Gav&amp;iacute;n Benavent, Javier Mart&amp;iacute;nez Ubieto, Carmen Gloria Nogueiras Quintas, Pablo Royo Dachary, Jorge Subira R&amp;iacute;os. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rub&amp;eacute;n Casans Franc&amp;eacute;s, has been paid professional fees by Merck Sharp &amp;amp; Dohme (MSD) for presentations. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emilio Del Valle Hern&amp;aacute;ndez, has received funding from MSD to attend meetings, congresses, and courses. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M&amp;ordf; Jes&amp;uacute;s Gil Sanz, has received financing from Astellas and Ipsen to attend meetings, congresses, and courses, and has received professional fees from Abbvie y Janssen for presentations. Juan Ignacio Mart&amp;iacute;n S&amp;aacute;nchez has received funding from MSD to attend meetings, congresses, and courses. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;M&amp;ordf; Julia Oc&amp;oacute;n Bret&amp;oacute;n, has received financing from Braun, Fresenius, Nutricia, Nestle, Sanofi, MSD, to attend meetings, congresses, and courses, has received professional fees from Abbott, Fresenius, Nutricia for presentations. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Jos&amp;eacute; Manuel Ram&amp;iacute;rez Rodr&amp;iacute;guez, has received professional fees from MSD for presentations, and has received economic aid for the financing of a research study from the Universidad de Zaragoza and IACS. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following external reviewers have declared that they have no conflicts of interests: Fernando Gilsanz Rodr&amp;iacute;guez, Luis Martos Garc&amp;iacute;a, Jos&amp;eacute; Luis Matute M&amp;iacute;nguez, Carlos Moreno Sanz, Jos&amp;eacute; Vicente Roig Vila. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Alfredo Abad Gurumeta, has received financing from Edwards Lifesciences, MSD, Abbvie and Berins &amp;amp; Co. to attend congresses, and professional fees as a speaker from MSD. He has also received financing from MSD to take courses, and professional fees as a consultant for the company Altan Pharma. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cristina de la Cuerda Compes has received financing from Nestle Health Science to attend a congress, professional fees as a speaker, and financing for participating in a research study. She has also received financing from Vegenat and Nutricia to take courses, and professional fees as a consultant for Shire. Alfredo Rodr&amp;iacute;guez Antol&amp;iacute;n has received financing from Astellas Pharma, Janssen Pharmaceutica and Ipsen to attend congresses. He has received financing from the Foundation for Biomedical Research of the Hospital Universitario 12 de Octubre to take a course for the unit, and economic aid to hire staff in the unit or service. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following expert collaborators have declared that they have no conflicts of interests: Luis Enrique Mu&amp;ntilde;oz Alameda and Luis Quecedo Guti&amp;eacute;rrez. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Francisco Faus Gaband&amp;eacute;, has received financing from the Universidad de Valencia to attend meetings, congresses, and courses. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Emilia Victoria Guasch Ar&amp;eacute;valo, has received financing from Behring financing to attend a congress and professional fees as a speaker. She has also received professional fees as a consultant for MSD and financing to take a course in her unit. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Juan Jos&amp;eacute; Hern&amp;aacute;ndez Aguado, has received financing from Roche to attend meetings, congresses, and courses. He has received professional fees as a speaker from Pfizer, Sanofi and Amgen. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Carmelo Loinaz Segurola has received financing from The Transplantation Society and Novartis to attend a congress and professional fees from Shire, Biotest Medical SLU, Fundaci&amp;oacute;n Oncosur, Roche, Vegenat, and MSD for presentations. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Manuel Romero Sim&amp;oacute;, has received financing from Ethicon to attend a congress. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Victoriano Soria Aledo, has received financing from Sanofi to attend a meeting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Available in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guiasalud.es/GPC/GPC_555_CMA_IACS_compl_en.pdf&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site (English Version)&quot;&gt;English&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guiasalud.es/GPC/GPC_555_CMA_IACS_compl.pdf&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site (Spanish Version)&quot;&gt;Spanish&lt;/a&gt; from the Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Quick reference guides and summary versions are available in Spanish from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://portal.guiasalud.es/web/guest/gpc-sns&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site&quot;&gt;Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Methodological material. Madrid (Spain): Aragon Institute for Health Sciences (IACS); 2016. 172 p. Available in Spanish from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guiasalud.es/GPC/GPC_555_CMA_IACS_mat_met.pdf&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site&quot;&gt;Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Grupo de trabajo sobre GPC. Elaboraci&amp;oacute;n de gu&amp;iacute;as de pr&amp;aacute;ctica cl&amp;iacute;nica en el Sistema Nacional de Salud. Actualizaci&amp;oacute;n del manual metodol&amp;oacute;gico. Madrid: Plan Nacional para el SNS del MSC. Instituto Aragon&amp;eacute;s de Ciencias de la Salud - I+CS; 2016. Gu&amp;iacute;as de pr&amp;aacute;ctica cl&amp;iacute;nica en el SNS: I+CS, n&amp;ordm; 2006/1. Available&amp;nbsp; in Spanish from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://portal.guiasalud.es/emanuales/elaboracion_2/&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site&quot;&gt;Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Working Group for CPG Updates. Updating clinical practice guidelines in the National Health System: methodology handbook. Madrid (Spain): National Health System Quality Plan of the Spanish Ministry of Health and Social Policy; Aragon Institute for Health Sciences (IACS); 2009. 67 p. (Clinical Practice Guidelines in the National Health System: IACS; no. 2007/02-01). Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guiasalud.es/emanuales/traduccion/ingles/manual_actualizacion/documentos/MMA_VersionEnglish_DEFINITIVA_10122_FIN.pdf&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site&quot;&gt;Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The Spanish version of the guideline is also available via a mobile application from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://portal.guiasalud.es/web/guest/app&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site&quot;&gt;Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="Patient information can be found in the Annex of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guiasalud.es/GPC/GPC_555_CMA_IACS_compl_en.pdf&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site (English Version)&quot;&gt;original guideline document&lt;/a&gt;. A Spanish version is also available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.guiasalud.es/GPC/GPC_555_CMA_IACS_paciente.pdf&quot; title=&quot;GuíaSalud Web site (Spanish Version)&quot;&gt;Gu&amp;iacute;aSalud Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Disclaimer&quot;&gt;Please note: This patient information is intended to provide health professionals with information to share with their patients to help them better understand their health and their diagnosed disorders. By providing access to this patient information, it is not the intention of NGC to provide specific medical advice for particular patients. Rather we urge patients and their representatives to review this material and then to consult with a licensed health professional for evaluation of treatment options suitable for them as well as for diagnosis and answers to their personal medical questions. This patient information has been derived and prepared from a guideline for health care professionals included on NGC by the authors or publishers of that original guideline. The patient information is not reviewed by NGC to establish whether or not it accurately reflects the original guideline's content.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on May 3, 2018. The information was verified by the guideline developer on May 22, 2018. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This NEATS assessment was completed by ECRI Institute on May 9, 2018. The information was verified by the guideline developer on May 22, 2018. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary is based on the original guideline, which is subject to the guideline developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse™ (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>