<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Reis SP, Majdalany BS, AbuRahma AF, Collins JD, Francois CJ, Ganguli S, Gornik HL, Kendi AT, Khaja MS, Norton PT, Sutphin PD, Rybicki FJ, Kalva SP, Expert Panel on Vascular Imaging. ACR Appropriateness Criteria® pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2016. 10 p.  [84 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline updates a previous version: Desjardins B, Rybicki FJ, Dill KE, Flamm SD, Francois CJ, Gerhard-Herman MD, Kalva SP, Mansour MA, Mohler ER III, Oliva IB, Schenker MP, Weiss C, Expert Panel on Vascular Imaging. ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm. [online publication]. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2012. 6 p. [65 references]&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Clinical Condition&lt;/span&gt;: Pulsatile Abdominal Mass, Suspected Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Variant 1:&lt;/span&gt; Pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Variant 1: Pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm.&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;thead&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th width=&quot;30%&quot; class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Radiologic Procedure&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th width=&quot;15%&quot; class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Rating&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th width=&quot;40%&quot; class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Comments&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th width=&quot;25%&quot; class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;RRL*&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/thead&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;US aorta abdomen&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;CTA abdomen with IV contrast&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;MRA abdomen without and with IV contrast&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;CT abdomen without IV contrast&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;CT abdomen with IV contrast&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;CT abdomen without and with IV contrast&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;MRA abdomen without IV contrast&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Aortography abdomen&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;FDG-PET/CT abdomen&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tfoot&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Rating Scale&lt;/span&gt;: 1,2,3 Usually not appropriate; 4,5,6 May be appropriate; 7,8,9 Usually appropriate&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;*Relative Radiation Level&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tfoot&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Note: Abbreviations used in the table are listed at the end of the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Summary of Literature Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Introduction/Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Clinical palpation of a pulsating abdominal mass alerts the clinician to the presence of a possible abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA), a common vascular disorder seen in older individuals, more commonly in male patients with a history of hypertension and smoking. However, the finding of a pulsatile abdominal mass can also be caused by a tortuous abdominal aorta or transmitted pulsations from the aorta to a nonvascular mass.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Generally, an arterial aneurysm is defined as a localized arterial dilatation &amp;ge;50% of the normal diameter. The term &lt;em&gt;ectasia&lt;/em&gt; is applied to arterial dilatations &amp;lt;50% of expected normal diameter. However, the normal dimension of the infrarenal abdominal aorta is up to 2 cm in anteroposterior (AP) diameter. Thus, the infrarenal abdominal aorta is considered aneurysmal if it is &amp;ge;3 cm in diameter or ectatic if it is between 2 and 3 cm in diameter. The absolute threshold for aneurysm decreases along the length of the aorta and is about 10% smaller in women than in men.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Imaging studies are important in diagnosing the cause of a pulsatile abdominal mass and, if an AAA is found, in determining its size, involvement of abdominal branches (both visceral and parietal), and any associated significant stenosis or aneurysm involving abdominal visceral and extremity arteries that may aid in treatment planning. Imaging studies should also categorize the extent of aneurysm (i.e., infrarenal aorta; infrarenal aorta and iliac artery; isolated iliac artery; or juxtarenal, suprarenal, or thoracoabdominal aorta). Imaging can also be used for routine surveillance of AAAs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Currently, elective repair is considered for AAAs &amp;ge;5.5 cm in diameter. For smaller AAAs, periodic surveillance is recommended at intervals based on their maximum size: every 6 months for those 4.5 to 5.4 cm in diameter, every 12 months for those 3.5 to 4.4 cm in diameter, every 3 years for those 3.0 to 3.4 cm in diameter, and every 5 years for those 2.6 to 2.9 cm in diameter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Population-based ultrasound (US) screening studies have been recommended and have proved cost-effective for male patients &amp;gt;65 years of age, despite the fact that one-fifth of all ruptured AAAs occur in these patients. The risk of AAA increases with a history of hypertension, smoking, 3-vessel coronary artery disease, and first-degree male relative with AAA. For AAAs 3 to 5.5 cm in diameter, periodic US or computed tomography (CT) imaging at 6- to 12-month intervals, depending on the rate of aneurysm enlargement on prior studies, is recommended. Other aneurysm characteristics, including saccular morphology of smaller aneurysms, have been associated with an increased risk of rupture below the 5.5-cm size threshold for intervention, and CT angiography (CTA) may be helpful in describing aneurysm morphology in patients with 4.0- to 5.5-cm aneurysms before continued US surveillance. When aneurysms have reached the size threshold for intervention (5.5 cm) or are considered clinically symptomatic, additional preintervention imaging studies should be performed to help define the optimal surgical or endovascular approach.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For preintervention studies, either multidetector CT (MDCT) or CTA is the optimal choice. Magnetic resonance angiography (MRA) may be substituted if CT cannot be performed (for example, because the patient is allergic to iodinated contrast material). However, MRA is usually performed with gadolinium contrast material, which is not suitable for patients with severe renal insufficiency. In such patients, the center where it is being performed must be able to perform MRA of AAAs without the use of gadolinium contrast material.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other types of imaging studies that have been used in the past to delineate AAAs&amp;mdash;including abdominal radiographs, intravenous urography and blood pool radionuclide imaging&amp;mdash;are not recommended for diagnosis, surveillance or preintervention imaging.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Catheter arteriography has very limited utility in the preintervention evaluation of patients with AAAs, its sole utility being in patients with significant contraindications to both CTA (significant renal dysfunction) and MRA (significant renal dysfunction, cardiac pacemakers, claustrophobia). In patients with significant renal dysfunction, the combination of CT and the lower load of iodinated contrast material that can be used with intra-arterial injection may decrease the risk of contrast-induced nephropathy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many imaging studies for assessing AAA can also identify other diseases that could affect preoperative management of AAA, such as coronary artery disease and thoracic aortic aneurysm. Screening for AAA can also be performed during unrelated imaging studies, such as transthoracic echocardiography, peripheral vascular US, and imaging studies to assess coronary artery disease and stroke or transient ischemic attack. Aortic root size measured by transthoracic echocardiography has been shown to be an independent predictor of AAA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ultrasound&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;US examination of the abdominal aorta should be a dedicated examination and not a component of a generalized abdominal US study. If possible, complete longitudinal evaluation of the full extent of the aneurysm and involvement of common iliac arteries should be performed. These studies should include a measurement of the leading-edge to leading-edge AP diameter in the proximal, mid, and distal infrarenal aorta and of the common iliac arteries. The presence of mural thrombus has been associated with expansion rates and should be delineated. Right and left kidneys should be imaged to determine size, parenchymal thickness, and presence or absence of hydronephrosis. In order to permit US to be used instead of CT for AAA follow-up, interindividual reproducibility of diameter measurements should be within &amp;le;4 mm. US tends to underestimate the size of aneurysms by 4 mm compared with CTA. Color Doppler imaging is not a necessary component of sonographic screening or surveillance examination. New, 3-dimensional (3-D) volumetric US techniques offer similar measurements but speed up imaging significantly.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Approximately 5% of AAAs will be juxtarenal or juxta/suprarenal, and it may not be possible to accurately delineate the upper margin of such aneurysms or the precise involvement of abdominal visceral branches by sonographic study. That is why a more definitive study, such as CTA, should be performed prior to intervention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computed Tomography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CT abdomen without contrast is diagnostically equivalent to US for AAA detection and is recommended in patients for whom US is not suitable. CT may be used as a diagnostic and preintervention study, suitable for patients presenting with pulsatile abdominal mass with or without clinical suspicion of contained aortic rupture and in planning endovascular or surgical intervention in patients with AAAs &amp;gt;5.5 cm in external AP diameter. In tortuous aneurysms, where a single dimension may be artifactually accentuated by the curvature of the aorta, the diameter of the aorta should be measured using multiplanar reformatted images that have been angle corrected for aortic curvature or curved planar reformatted images with automated centerline 3-D software.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CT abdomen with contrast provides some of the information that a CTA provides, such as aneurysm size, presence or absence of thrombus, and presence or absence of a dissection flap. CT abdomen with contrast does not give the precise size measurements, may not provide as much information about branch vessel involvement, and will not give the smooth 3-D renderings that a CTA will provide. However, CT abdomen with contrast performed in the portal venous phase provides more useful diagnostic information about extra-aortic pathology, such as liver, renal, and splenic pathology.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CT abdomen without and with contrast should be performed in patients with suspected contained rupture. CT without contrast is performed prior to CT with contrast to better diagnose dissecting hematoma in the lining of the intra-aortic thrombus (the crescent sign) and other signs consistent with imminent or contained rupture, including a draped aorta and adjacent vertebral erosion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Computed Tomography Angiography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the purposes of distinguishing between CT and CTA, ACR Appropriateness Criteria topics use the definition in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/PGTS/guidelines/Body_CTA.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;Practice Parameter for the Performance and Interpretation of Body Computed Tomography Angiography&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&quot;CTA uses a thin-section CT acquisition that is timed to coincide with peak arterial or venous enhancement. The resultant volumetric dataset is interpreted using primary transverse reconstructions as well as multiplanar reformations and 3-D renderings.&quot;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All elements are essential: (1) timing, (2) recons/reformats, and (3) 3-D renderings. Standard CTs with contrast also include timing issues and recons/reformats. Only in CTA, however, is 3-D rendering a required element. This corresponds to the definitions that the Centers for Medicare &amp;amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) have applied to the Current Procedural Terminology (CPT) codes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contrast-enhanced multidetector CTA is the best diagnostic and preintervention planning study, accurately delineating the location, size, and extent of aneurysm and the involvement of branch vessels, allowing for accurate quantitative 3-D measurements. CTA can also assess thrombus in aneurysm. The presence of thrombus affects the hemodynamic properties of the aorta. Larger thrombus and eccentric thrombus seem associated with rapid enlargement of the aneurysm and increased incidence of cardiovascular events. There are several research protocols that use modern CT technologies. Multiphase MDCT can assess compressibility of thrombus that can act as a biomechanical buffer. Using delayed imaging, aortic wall enhancement is associated with AAA diameter, biochemical markers of inflammation, and thrombus size. A grading scale based on CTA-derived biomechanical markers may predict aneurysm rupture. Short-term follow up by CTA does not decrease the suitability of aneurysms for endovascular intervention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In patients with a suspected thoracoabdominal aortic aneurysm, CTA may be tailored for an angiographic examination of the chest, abdomen, and pelvis. In patients with suspected coexistent lower-extremity arterial disease, the arterial system from the diaphragm to the feet can be studied with MDCT or CTA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Volume rendering, subvolume maximum intensity projection (MIP), and curved planar reformations are integral components of the 3-D analysis. Three-dimensional analysis is useful for measuring the correct size of an AAA. Semiautomated measurements of vessel diameter and length in relation to the proximal and distal aneurysm margins and branch vessels can be readily obtained with software supplied by multiple vendors. Additional research methods include electrocardiography (ECG)-gated MDCT that can assess decreased distensibility of aortic aneurysms. Advanced postprocessing of CT data can assess wall stress. Rapidly expanding AAAs have higher shoulder and wall stress. Calcification of the aneurysm increases wall stress and decreases the biomechanical stability of AAA. AAA peak wall stress at maximal blood pressure is higher in symptomatic or ruptured aneurysms compared to asymptomatic aneurysms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In patients who have a contained rupture, a rapid CT angiographic study provides a template for decision-making about endovascular aneurysm repair or surgical aneurysmectomy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Dual-energy CT and spectral CT have promise in the evaluation of patients with AAA. Both have the ability to create virtual noncontrast images, eliminating the need for true noncontrast images, with a potential for radiation dose reduction.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magnetic Resonance Angiography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Contrast-enhanced MRA is an alternative and effective diagnostic and preintervention study. The acquisition speed and spatial resolution of contrast-enhanced MRA has improved with the introduction of parallel imaging techniques, narrowing the gap with CTA in relation to image quality. The introduction of blood pool contrast agents now enables longer image acquisition to improve image resolution. Caution should be used in patients with severe renal dysfunction, generally considered as estimated glomerular filtration rate (GFR) &amp;lt;30 mL/kg/minute, who may be at risk for nephrogenic systemic fibrosis. In these patients, a non&amp;ndash;contrast-enhanced study may be substituted. Sequences and imaging expertise required for a full evaluation of AAA without contrast are becoming more mainstream.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Three-dimensional display techniques, including multiplanar reformation, MIP display, and volume rendering, are integral to the display and analysis of 3-D MRA. Cine techniques can also assess distensibility and, with suitable measurements of central venous pressure, can assess aortic compliance. Vessel wall shear stress can also be measured using newer 4-D flow-sensitive MRI techniques.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Catheter Arteriography (Aortography Abdomen)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Patients with significant contraindications to both CTA and MRA may have diagnostic catheter arteriography performed with a relatively low contrast material load following US documentation of AAA and/or noncontrast CT findings. Carbon dioxide may also be used as an alternative contrast agent for arteriography.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Catheter arteriography may not demonstrate the aneurysm diameter accurately, as only the contrast column of an aneurysm containing lining mural thrombus may be displayed. In patients with marginal renal function, rapid intra-arterial injection of a relatively low volume of dilute contrast material from a catheter located in the mid descending thoracic aorta can be used for a diagnostic CTA study, a technique called catheter-directed CTA.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positron Emission Tomography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although primarily a research tool, positron emission tomography using fluorine-18-2-fluoro-2-deoxy-D-glucose (FDG-PET) imaging has promise in the evaluation of patients with AAA. Increased metabolic activity and FDG uptake (maximum standardized uptake value &amp;gt;2.5) are noted in aneurysms and are even higher in infected aneurysms, inflammatory aneurysms, and symptomatic aneurysms and correlate well with histologic and metabolic evidence of inflammation. Increased FDG uptake is also seen in areas of high wall stress and rupture. Aneurysm calcification is unrelated to FDG uptake. More recently, FDG uptake has not been shown to be a predictor of aneurysm growth.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The consensus of the literature supports aortic US as the initial imaging modality of choice when a pulsatile abdominal mass is present. Noncontrast CT may be substituted in patients for whom US is not suitable (for example, those with obese body habitus). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;US is recommended as a screening technique in the Medicare-eligible male population at highest risk. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;For definitive diagnosis and preintervention imaging, CTA and MRA are recommended. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Currently, CTA is regarded as the superior test, as it is readily available, is robust, and provides high-spatial-resolution 3-D displays suitable for interventional planning as well as delineation of pathology in abdominal visceral arterial branches and extremity outflow vessels. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Contrast-enhanced MRA has improved significantly in terms of speed and spatial resolution with the advent of parallel processing techniques and blood pool contrast agents. It may replace CTA for interventional planning in patients for whom iodinated contrast is contraindicated. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Noncontrast MRA sequences for full evaluation of AAA are becoming more mainstream and should only be performed in centers with expertise in this technique. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Appropriate preintervention measurements of the aortoiliac arterial system can be obtained with either technique. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Both CTA and MRA can be used for thoracoabdominal aortic and extremity studies, all in the same imaging session. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;FDG-PET remains primarily a research tool but shows promise for assessing the metabolic activity of aneurysms. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abbreviations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;CT, computed tomography &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;CTA, computed tomography angiography &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;FDG-PET, fluorine-18-2-fluoro-2-deoxy-D-glucose positron emission tomography &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;IV, intravenous &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;MRA, magnetic resonance angiography &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;US, ultrasound &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relative Radiation Level Designations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;table width=&quot;50%&quot; border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;3&quot; cellpadding=&quot;5&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Relative Radiation Level Designations&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;thead&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Relative Radiation Level*&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Adult Effective Dose Estimate Range&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Pediatric Effective Dose Estimate Range&lt;/th&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/thead&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;O&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;0 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;0 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;0.1 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;0.03 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;0.1-1 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;0.03-0.3 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;1-10 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;0.3-3 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;10-30 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;3-10 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;&lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt; &lt;img alt=&quot;radioactive&quot; src=&quot;http://guideline.gov/images/image_radioactive.gif &quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;30-100 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;10-30 mSv&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; colspan=&quot;3&quot;&gt;*RRL assignments for some of the examinations cannot be made, because the actual patient doses in these procedures vary as a function of a number of factors (e.g., region of the body exposed to ionizing radiation, the imaging guidance that is used). The RRLs for these examinations are designated as &quot;Varies.&quot;&lt;/td&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Algorithms were not developed from criteria guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Diagnosis" />
      <FieldValue Value="Evaluation" />
      <FieldValue Value="Screening" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Cardiology" />
      <FieldValue Value="Family Practice" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Nuclear Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Radiology" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Health Care Providers" />
      <FieldValue Value="Health Plans" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospitals" />
      <FieldValue Value="Managed Care Organizations" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Assistants" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physicians" />
      <FieldValue Value="Students" />
      <FieldValue Value="Utilization Management" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To evaluate the appropriateness of imaging procedures for a pulsatile abdominal mass and suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients with a pulsatile abdominal mass and a suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Ultrasound (US) aorta, abdomen &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Computed tomographic angiography (CTA), abdomen with intravenous (IV) contrast &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Magnetic resonance angiography (MRA), abdomen&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Without and with IV contrast &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Without IV contrast &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Computed tomography (CT), abdomen&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Without IV contrast &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;With IV contrast &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;        &lt;li&gt;Without and with IV contrast &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Aortography, abdomen &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Fluorine-18-2-fluoro-2-deoxy-D-glucose positron emission tomography (FDG-PET)/CT, abdomen &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Utility of imaging procedures in the diagnosis and evaluation of pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected aortic aneurysm &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sensitivity, specificity, and accuracy of imaging procedures in the diagnosis and evaluation pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected aortic aneurysm &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Primary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Secondary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Literature Search Summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the 65 citations in the original bibliography, 57 were retained in the final document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A literature search was conducted in April 2015 and June 2016 to identify additional evidence published since the &lt;em&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; Pulsatile Abdominal Mass&amp;ndash;Suspected Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm&lt;/em&gt; topic was finalized. Using the search strategies described in the literature search companion (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field), 2624 articles were found. Twenty-one articles were added to the bibliography. Eighty-eight articles were not used as they were duplicates already cited in the original bibliography or captured in more than one literature search. The remaining articles were not used due to either poor study design, the articles were not relevant or generalizable to the topic, or the results were unclear or biased.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The author added 5 citations from bibliographies, Web sites, or books that were not found in the literature searches.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One citation is a supporting document that was added by staff.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;See also the American College of Radiology (ACR) Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; literature search process document (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field) for further information.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the 65 citations in the original bibliography, 57 were retained in the final document. The literature search conducted in April 2015 and June 2016 identified 21 articles that were added to the bibliography. The author added 5 citations from bibliographies, Web sites, or books that were not found in the literature searches. One citation is a supporting document that was added by staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Definitions of Study Quality Categories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Category 1 - The study is well-designed and accounts for common biases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Category 2 - The study is moderately well-designed and accounts for most common biases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Category 3 - The study has important study design limitations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Category 4 - The study or source is not useful as primary evidence. The article may not be a clinical study, the study design is invalid, or conclusions are based on expert consensus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;The study does not meet the criteria for or is not a hypothesis-based clinical study (e.g., a book chapter or case report or case series description);&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;The study may synthesize and draw conclusions about several studies such as a literature review article or book chapter but is not primary evidence;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Or&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Indent&quot;&gt;The study is an expert opinion or consensus document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Category M - Meta-analysis studies are not rated for study quality using the study element method because the method is designed to evaluate individual studies only. An &quot;M&quot; for the study quality will indicate that the study quality has not been evaluated for the meta-analysis study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review with Evidence Tables" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The topic author assesses the literature then drafts or revises the narrative summarizing the evidence found in the literature. American College of Radiology (ACR) staff drafts an evidence table based on the analysis of the selected literature. These tables rate the study quality for each article included in the narrative.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The expert panel reviews the narrative, evidence table and the supporting literature for each of the topic-variant combinations and assigns an appropriateness rating for each procedure listed in the variant table(s). Each individual panel member assigns a rating based on his/her interpretation of the available evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;More information about the evidence table development process can be found in the ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; Evidence Table Development document (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus (Delphi)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Rating Appropriateness&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The American College of Radiology (ACR) Appropriateness Criteria methodology is based on the RAND Appropriateness Method. The appropriateness ratings for each of the procedures or treatments included in the Appropriateness Criteria topics are determined using a modified Delphi method. A series of surveys are conducted to elicit each panelist's expert interpretation of the evidence, based on the available data, regarding the appropriateness of an imaging or therapeutic procedure for a specific clinical scenario. The expert panel members review the evidence presented and assess the risks or harms of doing the procedure balanced with the benefits of performing the procedure. The direct or indirect costs of a procedure are not considered as a risk or harm when determining appropriateness. When the evidence for a specific topic and variant is uncertain or incomplete, expert opinion may supplement the available evidence or may be the sole source for assessing the appropriateness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The appropriateness is represented on an ordinal scale that uses integers from 1 to 9 grouped into three categories: 1, 2, or 3 are in the category &quot;usually not appropriate&quot; where the harms of doing the procedure outweigh the benefits; and 7, 8, or 9 are in the category &quot;usually appropriate&quot; where the benefits of doing a procedure outweigh the harms or risks. The middle category, designated &quot;may be appropriate,&quot; is represented by 4, 5, or 6 on the scale. The middle category is when the risks and benefits are equivocal or unclear, the dispersion of the individual ratings from the group median rating is too large (i.e., disagreement), the evidence is contradictory or unclear, or there are special circumstances or subpopulations which could influence the risks or benefits that are embedded in the variant.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The ratings assigned by each panel member are presented in a table displaying the frequency distribution of the ratings without identifying which members provided any particular rating. To determine the panel's recommendation, the rating category that contains the median group rating without disagreement is selected. This may be determined after either the first or second rating round. If there is disagreement after the second rating round, the recommendation is &quot;May be appropriate.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This modified Delphi method enables each panelist to articulate his or her individual interpretations of the evidence or expert opinion without excessive influence from fellow panelists in a simple, standardized, and economical process. For additional information on the ratings process see the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/AppCriteria/RatingRoundInfo.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;Rating Round Information&lt;/a&gt; document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additional methodology documents, including a more detailed explanation of the complete topic development process and all ACR Appropriateness Criteria topics can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acr.org/Quality-Safety/Appropriateness-Criteria&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt; (see also the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Population-based ultrasound (US) screening studies have been recommended and have proved cost-effective for male patients &amp;gt;65 years of age, despite the fact that one-fifth of all ruptured abdominal aortic aneurysms (AAAs) occur in these patients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Criteria developed by the Expert Panels are reviewed by the American College of Radiology (ACR) Committee on Appropriateness Criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recommendations are based on analysis of the current medical evidence literature and the application of the RAND/UCLA appropriateness method and expert panel consensus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Summary of Evidence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of the 84 references cited in the &lt;em&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; Pulsatile Abdominal Mass, Suspected Abdominal Aortic Aneurysm&lt;/em&gt; document, 1 is a good-quality therapeutic reference. Additionally, 82 references are categorized as diagnostic references including 10 good-quality studies, and 15 quality studies that may have design limitations. There are 56 references that may not be useful as primary evidence. One reference is a meta-analysis study.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although there are references that report on studies with design limitations, 22 well-designed or good-quality studies provide good evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imaging studies are important in diagnosing the cause of a pulsatile abdominal mass and, if an abdominal aortic aneurysm (AAA) is found, in determining its size, involvement of abdominal branches (both visceral and parietal), and any associated significant stenosis or aneurysm involving abdominal visceral and extremity arteries that may aid in treatment planning. Imaging studies should also categorize the extent of aneurysm (i.e., infrarenal aorta; infrarenal aorta and iliac artery; isolated iliac artery; or juxtarenal, suprarenal, or thoracoabdominal aorta). Imaging can also be used for routine surveillance of AAAs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Caution should be used when administering contrast in patients with severe renal dysfunction, generally considered as estimated glomerular filtration rate &amp;lt;30 mL/kg/min, who may be at risk for nephrogenic systemic fibrosis. In these patients, a non&amp;ndash;contrast-enhanced study may be substituted.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Relative Radiation Level Information&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Potential adverse health effects associated with radiation exposure are an important factor to consider when selecting the appropriate imaging procedure. Because there is a wide range of radiation exposures associated with different diagnostic procedures, a relative radiation level (RRL) indication has been included for each imaging examination. The RRLs are based on effective dose, which is a radiation dose quantity that is used to estimate population total radiation risk associated with an imaging procedure. Patients in the pediatric age group are at inherently higher risk from exposure, both because of organ sensitivity and longer life expectancy (relevant to the long latency that appears to accompany radiation exposure). For these reasons, the RRL dose estimate ranges for pediatric examinations are lower as compared to those specified for adults. Additional information regarding radiation dose assessment for imaging examinations can be found in the American College of Radiology (ACR) Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; Radiation Dose Assessment Introduction document (see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="430" OrdBy="800" Name="Contraindications">
    <Field FieldID="144" OrdBy="805" ID="431" Name="Contraindications" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Significant renal dysfunction is a contraindication for computed tomography angiography (CTA). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Significant renal dysfunction, cardiac pacemakers, and claustrophobia are contraindications for magnetic resonance angiography (MRA). &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The American College of Radiology (ACR) Committee on Appropriateness Criteria and its expert panels have developed criteria for determining appropriate imaging examinations for diagnosis and treatment of specified medical condition(s). These criteria are intended to guide radiologists, radiation oncologists, and referring physicians in making decisions regarding radiologic imaging and treatment. Generally, the complexity and severity of a patient's clinical condition should dictate the selection of appropriate imaging procedures or treatments. Only those examinations generally used for evaluation of the patient's condition are ranked. Other imaging studies necessary to evaluate other co-existent diseases or other medical consequences of this condition are not considered in this document. The availability of equipment or personnel may influence the selection of appropriate imaging procedures or treatments. Imaging techniques classified as investigational by the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) have not been considered in developing these criteria; however, study of new equipment and applications should be encouraged. The ultimate decision regarding the appropriateness of any specific radiologic examination or treatment must be made by the referring physician and radiologist in light of all the circumstances presented in an individual examination. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR seeks and encourages collaboration with other organizations on the development of the ACR Appropriateness Criteria through society representation on expert panels. Participation by representatives from collaborating societies on the expert panel does not necessarily imply society endorsement of the final document. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An implementation strategy was not provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Reis SP, Majdalany BS, AbuRahma AF, Collins JD, Francois CJ, Ganguli S, Gornik HL, Kendi AT, Khaja MS, Norton PT, Sutphin PD, Rybicki FJ, Kalva SP, Expert Panel on Vascular Imaging. ACR Appropriateness Criteria® pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2016. 10 p.  [84 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2016" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="American College of Radiology - Medical Specialty Society" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The American College of Radiology (ACR) provided the funding and the resources for these ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Committee on Appropriateness Criteria, Expert Panel on Vascular Imaging&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Panel Members&lt;/em&gt;: Stephen P. Reis, MD (&lt;em&gt;Principal Author&lt;/em&gt;); Bill S. Majdalany, MD (&lt;em&gt;Panel Vice-chair&lt;/em&gt;); Ali F. AbuRahma, MD; Jeremy D. Collins, MD; Christopher J. Francois, MD; Suvranu Ganguli, MD; Heather L. Gornik, MD; A. Tuba Kendi, MD; Minhajuddin S. Khaja, MD, MBA; Patrick T. Norton, MD; Patrick D. Sutphin, MD, PhD; Frank J. Rybicki, MD, PhD (&lt;em&gt;Specialty Chair&lt;/em&gt;); Sanjeeva P. Kalva, MD (&lt;em&gt;Panel Chair&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not stated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline updates a previous version: Desjardins B, Rybicki FJ, Dill KE, Flamm SD, Francois CJ, Gerhard-Herman MD, Kalva SP, Mansour MA, Mohler ER III, Oliva IB, Schenker MP, Weiss C, Expert Panel on Vascular Imaging. ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm. [online publication]. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology (ACR); 2012. 6 p. [65 references]&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://acsearch.acr.org/docs/69414/Narrative/&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR) Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following are available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Overview. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2015 Oct. 3 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/AppCriteria/Overview.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;American College of Radiology (ACR) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Literature search process. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2015 Feb. 1 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/AppCriteria/LiteratureSearchProcess.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Evidence table development. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2015 Nov. 5 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/AppCriteria/EvidenceTableDevelopment.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Topic development process. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2015 Nov. 2 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/AppCriteria/TopicDevelopmentProcess.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Rating round information. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2015 Apr. 5 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/AppCriteria/RatingRoundInfo.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Radiation dose assessment introduction. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2016. 4 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/ACR/Documents/AppCriteria/RadiationDoseAssessmentIntro.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Manual on contrast media. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2016. 128 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/Quality-Safety/Resources/Contrast-Manual&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg;. Procedure information. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2016 May. 2 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.acr.org/~/media/E77E9964C8224151BE6D21A7CE68FEE4.pdf&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm. Evidence table. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2016. 39 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://acsearch.acr.org/docs/69414/EvidenceTable/&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;ACR Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; pulsatile abdominal mass, suspected abdominal aortic aneurysm. Literature search. Reston (VA): American College of Radiology; 2016. 2 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://acsearch.acr.org/docs/69414/LitSearch/&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None available&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary was completed by ECRI on February 20, 2001. The information was verified by the guideline developer on March 14, 2001. This summary was updated by ECRI on March 6, 2006. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on May 17, 2007 following the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) advisory on Gadolinium-based contrast agents. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on June 20, 2007 following the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) advisory on gadolinium-based contrast agents. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on June 8, 2010. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on January 13, 2011 following the U.S. Food and Drug Administration (FDA) advisory on gadolinium-based contrast agents. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on November 8, 2012. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on March 23, 2017.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Instructions for downloading, use, and reproduction of the American College of Radiology (ACR) Appropriateness Criteria&amp;reg; may be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.acr.org/Quality-Safety/Appropriateness-Criteria/TermsConditions&quot; title=&quot;ACR Web site&quot;&gt;ACR Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse™ (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>