<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Prediction and prevention. In: Diagnosis, evaluation, and management of the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy: executive summary.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Magee LA, Pels A, Helewa M, Rey E, von Dadelszen P, Hypertension Guideline Committee. Prediction and prevention. In: Diagnosis, evaluation, and management of the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy: executive summary. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2014 May;36(5):425-6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline updates a previous version: Magee LA, Helewa M, Moutquin JM, von Dadelszen P, Hypertension Guideline Committee, Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada. Prediction, prevention, and prognosis of preeclampsia. In: Diagnosis, evaluation, and management of the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2008 Mar;30(3 Suppl 1):S16-23.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Definitions of the quality of evidence assessment (&lt;strong&gt;I-III&lt;/strong&gt;) and classification of recommendations (&lt;strong&gt;A-E, L&lt;/strong&gt;) are provided at the end of the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Predicting Preeclampsia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Women should be screened for clinical risk markers of preeclampsia from early pregnancy. (&lt;strong&gt;II-2C&lt;/strong&gt;) See Table 6 in the original guideline document. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Consultation with an obstetrician or an obstetric internist, by telephone if necessary, should be considered for women with a history of previous preeclampsia or another strong clinical marker of increased preeclampsia risk, particularly multiple pregnancy, antiphospholipid antibody syndrome, significant proteinuria at first antenatal visit (usually early in pregnancy), or a pre-existing condition of hypertension, diabetes mellitus, or renal disease. (&lt;strong&gt;II-2B&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Screening using biomarkers or Doppler ultrasound velocimetry of the uteroplacental circulation cannot be recommended routinely at present for women at low or increased risk of preeclampsia until such screening has been shown to improve pregnancy outcome. (&lt;strong&gt;II-2C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preventing Preeclampsia and Its Complications in Women at Low Risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;4&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Calcium supplementation of at least 1 g/d, orally, is recommended for women with low dietary intake of calcium (&amp;lt;600 mg/d). (&lt;strong&gt;I-A&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The following are recommended for other established beneficial effects in pregnancy: abstention from alcohol for prevention of fetal alcohol effects (&lt;strong&gt;II-2E&lt;/strong&gt;), exercise for maintenance of fitness (&lt;strong&gt;I-A&lt;/strong&gt;), periconceptual use of a folate-containing multivitamin for prevention of neural tube defects (&lt;strong&gt;I-A&lt;/strong&gt;), and smoking cessation for prevention of low birthweight and preterm birth. (&lt;strong&gt;I-E&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Periconceptual and ongoing use of a folate-containing multivitamin (&lt;strong&gt;I-B&lt;/strong&gt;) or exercise (&lt;strong&gt;II-2B&lt;/strong&gt;) may be useful in preventing preeclampsia. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Prostaglandin precursors and supplementation with magnesium or zinc are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; recommended for preeclampsia prevention, but may be useful for prevention of other pregnancy complications. (&lt;strong&gt;I-C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Dietary salt restriction during pregnancy (&lt;strong&gt;I-D&lt;/strong&gt;), calorie restriction during pregnancy for overweight women (&lt;strong&gt;I-D&lt;/strong&gt;), low-dose acetylsalicylic acid (&lt;strong&gt;I-E&lt;/strong&gt;), vitamins C and E (based on current evidence) (&lt;strong&gt;I-E&lt;/strong&gt;), and thiazide diuretics (&lt;strong&gt;I-E&lt;/strong&gt;) are not recommended. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is insufficient evidence to make a recommendation about a heart-healthy diet (&lt;strong&gt;II-2L&lt;/strong&gt;); workload or stress reduction (including bedrest) (&lt;strong&gt;II-2L&lt;/strong&gt;); supplementation with iron with or without folate (&lt;strong&gt;I-L&lt;/strong&gt;); vitamin D (&lt;strong&gt;I-L&lt;/strong&gt;); pyridoxine (&lt;strong&gt;I-L&lt;/strong&gt;); or food rich in flavonoids. (&lt;strong&gt;I-L&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Preventing Preeclampsia and Its Complications in Women at Increased Risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;10&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Low-dose acetylsalicylic acid and calcium supplementation (of at least 1 g/d) for women with low calcium intake are recommended for preventions of preeclampsia in women at high risk. (&lt;strong&gt;I-A&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Acetylsalicylic acid should be: taken in a low dose (75 to 162 mg/d), (&lt;strong&gt;III-B&lt;/strong&gt;) administered at bedtime, (&lt;strong&gt;I-B&lt;/strong&gt;) initiated after diagnosis of pregnancy but before 16 weeks' gestation, (&lt;strong&gt;I-B&lt;/strong&gt;) and considered for continuation until delivery. (&lt;strong&gt;I-C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Prophylactic doses of low-molecular-weight heparin may be discussed in women with previous placental complications (including preeclampsia) to prevent the recurrence of severe or early-onset preeclampsia, preterm delivery, and/or infants that are small for gestational age. (&lt;strong&gt;I-B&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The following may be useful: L-arginine (&lt;strong&gt;I-B&lt;/strong&gt;), increased rest at home in the third trimester (&lt;strong&gt;I-C&lt;/strong&gt;), and reduction of workload or stress. (&lt;strong&gt;III-C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The following may be useful for prevention of other pregnancy complications: prostaglandin precursors (&lt;strong&gt;I-B&lt;/strong&gt;), magnesium supplementation (&lt;strong&gt;I-C&lt;/strong&gt;), and heparin to prevent venous thromboembolic disease. (&lt;strong&gt;I-B&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The following are recommended for other established beneficial effects in pregnancy (as discussed for women at low risk of preeclampsia): abstention from alcohol (&lt;strong&gt;II-2E&lt;/strong&gt;), periconceptual use of a folate-containing multivitamin (&lt;strong&gt;I-A&lt;/strong&gt;), and smoking cessation. (&lt;strong&gt;I-E&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The following are &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; recommended: calorie restriction in overweight women during pregnancy (&lt;strong&gt;I-D&lt;/strong&gt;), weight maintenance in obese women during pregnancy (&lt;strong&gt;III-D&lt;/strong&gt;), antihypertensive therapy specifically to prevent preeclampsia (&lt;strong&gt;I-D&lt;/strong&gt;), and vitamins C and E. (&lt;strong&gt;I-E&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is insufficient evidence to make a recommendation about the usefulness of the following: the heart-healthy diet (&lt;strong&gt;III-L&lt;/strong&gt;); exercise (&lt;strong&gt;I-L&lt;/strong&gt;); selenium (&lt;strong&gt;I-L&lt;/strong&gt;); garlic (&lt;strong&gt;I-L&lt;/strong&gt;); zinc, pyridoxine, iron (with or without folate), vitamin D, or multivitamins with/without micronutrients. (&lt;strong&gt;III-L&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of Evidence Assessment&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from at least one properly randomized controlled trial&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II-1&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence from well-designed controlled trials without randomization&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II-2&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence from well-designed cohort (prospective or retrospective) or case&amp;ndash;control studies, preferably from more than one centre or research group&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II-3&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from comparisons between times or places with or without the intervention. Dramatic results in uncontrolled experiments (such as the results of treatment with penicillin in the 1940s) could also be included in this category&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III&lt;/strong&gt;: Opinions of respected authorities, based on clinical experience, descriptive studies, or reports of expert committees&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Adapted from The Evaluation of Evidence criteria described in the Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification of Recommendations&amp;dagger;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;. There is good evidence to recommend the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt;. There is fair evidence to recommend the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;. The existing evidence is conflicting and does not allow to make a recommendation for or against use of the clinical preventive action; however, other factors may influence decision-making&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;. There is fair evidence to recommend against the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;. There is good evidence to recommend against the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;. There is insufficient evidence (in quantity or quality) to make a recommendation; however, other factors may influence decision-making&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&amp;dagger;Adapted from the Classification of Recommendations criteria described in the Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None provided&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preeclampsia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Prevention" />
      <FieldValue Value="Risk Assessment" />
      <FieldValue Value="Screening" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Family Practice" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Obstetrics and Gynecology" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Assistants" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physicians" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;To present in brief the current evidence assessed in the clinical practice guideline prepared by the Canadian Hypertensive Disorders of Pregnancy Working Group and published by &lt;em&gt;Pregnancy Hypertension&lt;/em&gt; to provide a reasonable approach to the diagnosis, evaluation, and treatment of the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy (HDP) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;To support evidence-based maternity care of women who are planning pregnancy and are at risk of a HDP, have an HDP in the current pregnancy, or are postpartum and had an HDP &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Women who are planning pregnancy and are at risk of a hypertensive disorder of pregnancy (HDP), have an HDP in the current pregnancy, or are postpartum and had an HDP&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Screening&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Screening for clinical risk markers &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Consultation with an obstetrician or an obstetric internist &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Screening using biomarkers or Doppler ultrasound velocimetry of the uteroplacental circulation (not routinely recommended) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Prevention&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women at Low Risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Calcium supplementation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Abstention from alcohol &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Exercise &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Folate-containing multivitamin &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Smoking cessation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The following interventions were considered but not recommended or there was insufficient evidence to make a recommendation: prostaglandin precursors, supplementation with magnesium or zinc, dietary salt restriction during pregnancy, calorie restriction during pregnancy (overweight women), low-dose acetylsalicylic acid, vitamins C and E, thiazide diuretics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Women at Increased Risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Low-dose acetylsalicylic acid &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Calcium supplementation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Prophylactic doses of low-molecular-weight heparin &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;L-arginine &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Increased rest at home in the third trimester and reduction of workload or stress &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Prostaglandin precursors and magnesium supplementation (for prevention of other pregnancy complications) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Abstention from alcohol &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Periconceptual use of folate-containing multivitamin &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Smoking cessation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The following interventions were considered but not recommended or there was insufficient evidence to make a recommendation: calorie restriction and weight maintenance (overweight/obese women), antihypertensive therapy specifically to prevent preeclampsia, vitamins C and E, heart-healthy diet, exercise, selenium, garlic, zinc, pyridoxine, iron (with or without folate), vitamin D, or multivitamins with/without micronutrients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Risk of development of preeclampsia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Maternal end-organ dysfunction &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Fetal manifestations of preeclampsia &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Preeclampsia imitators &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Maternal and perinatal morbidity &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Accuracy of all blood pressure measurement devices &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Unpublished Data" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Published literature was retrieved through searches of MEDLINE, Cumulative Index of Nursing and Allied Health Literature (CINAHL), and The Cochrane Library in March 2012 using appropriate controlled vocabulary (e.g., pregnancy, hypertension, pre-eclampsia, pregnancy toxemias) and key words (e.g., diagnosis, evaluation, classification, prediction, prevention, prognosis, treatment, postpartum follow-up). Results were restricted to systematic reviews, randomized control trials, controlled clinical trials, and observational studies published in French or English between January 2006 and February 2012. Searches were updated on a regular basis and incorporated in the guideline to September 2013. Grey (unpublished) literature was identified through searching the websites of health technology assessment and health technology-related agencies, clinical practice guideline collections, clinical trial registries, and national and international medical specialty societies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not stated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quality of Evidence Assessment*&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from at least one properly randomized controlled trial&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II-1&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence from well-designed controlled trials without randomization&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II-2&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence from well-designed cohort (prospective or retrospective) or case&amp;ndash;control studies, preferably from more than one centre or research group&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II-3&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from comparisons between times or places with or without the intervention. Dramatic results in uncontrolled experiments (such as the results of treatment with penicillin in the 1940s) could also be included in this category&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III&lt;/strong&gt;: Opinions of respected authorities, based on clinical experience, descriptive studies, or reports of expert committees&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Adapted from The Evaluation of Evidence criteria described in the Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The quality of evidence in the guideline summarized here was rated using the criteria described in the Report of the Canadian Task Force on Preventative Health Care (see the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not stated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Classification of Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;*&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt;. There is good evidence to recommend the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B.&lt;/strong&gt; There is fair evidence to recommend the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C&lt;/strong&gt;. The existing evidence is conflicting and does not allow to make a recommendation for or against use of the clinical preventive action; however, other factors may influence decision-making&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D&lt;/strong&gt;. There is fair evidence to recommend against the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E&lt;/strong&gt;. There is good evidence to recommend against the clinical preventive action&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;L&lt;/strong&gt;. There is insufficient evidence (in quantity or quality) to make a recommendation; however, other factors may influence decision-making&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;*Adapted from the Classification of Recommendations criteria described in the Canadian Task Force on Preventive Health Care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A formal cost analysis was not performed and published cost analyses were not reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The guideline has been prepared by the Canadian Hypertensive Disorders of Pregnancy Working Group, reviewed and approved by the Hypertension Guideline Committee, reviewed by the Maternal Fetal Medicine and Family Physician Advisory committees, and approved by the Executive and Council of the Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The type of supporting evidence is identified and graded for each recommendation (see the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The expected benefit of this guideline is improved outcomes for mother, baby, and child through evidence-advised practice.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not stated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This document reflects emerging clinical and scientific advances on the date issued and is subject to change. The information should not be construed as dictating an exclusive course of treatment or procedure to be followed. Local institutions can dictate amendments to these opinions. They should be well documented if modified at the local level. None of these contents may be reproduced in any form without prior written permission of the Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada (SOGC).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Appendix (see Table 10 in the full version of the original guideline document [see the &quot;Availability of Companion Documents&quot; field]) lists tools to support the application of this guideline. Some Web sites provide general information about blood pressure (BP) measurement for non-pregnant patients, but the recommendations are similar enough to those for pregnant women to be useful. Patients, their partners, and their care providers should be well educated about the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy (HDP), and relevant sites are listed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Implementation of any evidence depends on individual knowledge and beliefs, as well as institutional culture. Strong recommendations should be incorporated into clinical practice. In well-resourced settings, almost all preeclampsia-related maternal deaths involve substandard care.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some updates to the 2008 Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada (SOGC) guidelines on the HDP may require additional effort to implement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physicians should consider the category &quot;other HDP&quot; (white-coat and masked hypertension) as part of the classification of hypertensive women and consider using some form of out-of-office BP measurement to evaluate women with non-severe pre-existing or gestational hypertension.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Health care providers should inform pregnant women about the symptoms and signs of the HDPs and refer them to appropriate knowledge translation tools.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The developer recommends the use of corticosteroids for women &amp;le; 34+6 weeks' gestation who are at high risk of delivery within the next seven days. This gestational age cut-off represents a fundamental change in practice that will require discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physicians should be familiar with the blood bank policies of their own hospital.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Physicians should be aware of postpartum signs of maternal posttraumatic stress disorder and the maternal and perinatal long-term effects of HDPs, especially at this vulnerable time in maternal care when the maternity care provider is often handing back care to the primary care physician.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The reader is reminded to refer to the full open-access guideline published in Pregnancy Hypertension, which contains not only the recommendations presented here, but also all explanatory text and additional references.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="117" OrdBy="1015" ID="437" Name="Implementation Tools" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Foreign Language Translations" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
      <FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Magee LA, Pels A, Helewa M, Rey E, von Dadelszen P, Hypertension Guideline Committee. Prediction and prevention. In: Diagnosis, evaluation, and management of the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy: executive summary. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2014 May;36(5):425-6.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2008 Mar (revised 2014 May)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada - Medical Specialty Society" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Canadian Hypertensive Disorders of Pregnancy Working Group&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Principal Authors&lt;/em&gt;: Laura A. Magee, MD, Vancouver BC; Anouk Pels, MSc, Amsterdam, the Netherlands; Michael Helewa, MD, Winnipeg MB; Evelyne Rey, MD, Montreal QC; Peter von Dadelszen, MBChB, Vancouver BC&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Hypertension Guideline Committee Members&lt;/em&gt;: Laura A. Magee, MD (Chair), Vancouver BC; Francois Audibert, MD, Montreal QC; Emmanuel Bujold, MD, Quebec QC; Anne-Marie C&amp;ocirc;t&amp;eacute;, MD, Sherbrooke QC; Myrtle Joanne Douglas, MD, Vancouver BC; Genevieve Eastabrook, MD, FRCSC, London ON; Tabassum Firoz, MD, Vancouver BC; Paul Gibson, MD, Calgary AB; Andr&amp;eacute;e Gruslin, MD, Ottawa ON; Jennifer Hutcheon, PhD, Vancouver BC; Gideon Koren, MD, Toronto ON; Ian Lange, MD, Calgary AB; Line Leduc, MD, Montreal QC; Alexander G. Logan, MD, Toronto ON; Karen L. MacDonell, PhD, Vancouver BC; Jean-Marie Moutquin, MD, Sherbrooke QC; Ilana Sebbag, MD, Vancouver BC&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Disclosure statements have been received from all members of the committee.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline updates a previous version: Magee LA, Helewa M, Moutquin JM, von Dadelszen P, Hypertension Guideline Committee, Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada. Prediction, prevention, and prognosis of preeclampsia. In: Diagnosis, evaluation, and management of the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy. J Obstet Gynaecol Can. 2008 Mar;30(3 Suppl 1):S16-23.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electronic copies: Available in Portable Document Format (PDF) from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sogc.org/guidelines/diagnosis-evaluation-management-hypertensive-disorders-pregnancy-executive-summary/&quot; title=&quot;SOGC Web site&quot;&gt;Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada (SOGC) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. Also available in French from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://sogc.org/fr/guidelines/diagnostic-evaluation-et-prise-en-charge-des-troubles-hypertensifs-de-la-grossesse-resume-directif/&quot; title=&quot;SOGC Web site&quot;&gt;SOGC Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Print copies: Available from the Society of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists of Canada, La soci&amp;eacute;t&amp;eacute; des obst&amp;eacute;triciens et gyn&amp;eacute;cologues du Canada (SOGC) 780 promenade Echo Drive Ottawa, ON K1S 5R7 (Canada); Phone: 1-800-561-2416.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Magee LA, Pels A, Helewa M, Rey E, Von Dadelszen P, Canadian Hypertensive Disorders of Pregnancy (HDP) Working Group. Diagnosis, evaluation, and management of the hypertensive disorders of pregnancy. Pregnancy Hypertens. 2014 Apr;(4)2:104-45. Electronic copies: Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pregnancyhypertension.org/article/S2210-7789(14)00004-X/fulltext&quot; title=&quot;Pregnancy Hypertension: An International Journal of Women's Cardiovascular Health Web site&quot;&gt;Pregnancy Hypertension: An International Journal of Women's Cardiovascular Health Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None available&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on February 17, 2009. The information was verified by the guideline developer on March 13, 2009. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on June 5, 2014. The information was verified by the guideline developer on June 23, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary is based on the original guideline, which is subject to the guideline developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse™ (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>