<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Optimal timing of femur fracture stabilization in polytrauma patients: a practice management guideline from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gandhi RR, Overton TL, Haut ER, Lau B, Vallier HA, Rohs T, Hasenboehler E, Lee JK, Alley D, Watters J, Rogers FB, Shafi S. Optimal timing of femur fracture stabilization in polytrauma patients: a practice management guideline from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2014 Nov;77(5):787-95. [51 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EAST Practice Management Guidelines Work Group. Practice management guidelines for the optimal timing of long bone fracture stabilization. Winston-Salem (NC): Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST); 2000. 39 p. [25 references]&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strength of recommendation (&lt;strong&gt;strong&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;weak/conditional&lt;/strong&gt;) and levels of evidence (&lt;strong&gt;high&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;moderate&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;low&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;very low&lt;/strong&gt;) are defined at the end of the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In trauma patients with open or closed femur fractures, the panel suggests early (&amp;lt;24 hours) open reduction and internal fracture fixation. This recommendation is conditional, and the strength of the evidence is low. Early stabilization of femur fractures shows a trend (statistically insignificant) toward lower risk of infection, mortality, and venous thromboembolism (VTE). Therefore, the panel concludes that the desirable effects of early femur fracture stabilization probably outweigh the undesirable effects in most patients. &lt;strong&gt;Conditional recommendation (low quality of evidence)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Definitions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation (GRADE) Methodology Levels for Rating the Quality of Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation (GRADE) Methodology Levels for Rating the Quality of Evidence&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Quality Level&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Very confident that the true effect lies close to estimate of effect.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Moderate&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Moderate effect; true effect is likely close to estimate of effect but may be substantially different.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Low&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Limited confidence; true effect may be substantially different from estimate of effect&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Very Low&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Little confidence; true effect likely substantially different from estimate of effect.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GRADE Definition of Strong and Weak Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: GRADE Definition of Strong and Weak Recommendation&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Strong Recommendation&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Weak/Conditional Recommendation&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;For patients&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Most patients would want the recommended course of action.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Most patients would want the recommended course of action, but many would not.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;For clinicians&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Most patients should receive the recommended course of action.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Different choices will exist for different patients, and clinicians should help patients decide. &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;For policy makers &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Recommended course should be adopted as policy.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Considerable debate and stakeholder involvement needed to make policy.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None provided&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Femur fracture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Management" />
      <FieldValue Value="Treatment" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Critical Care" />
      <FieldValue Value="Emergency Medicine" />
      <FieldValue Value="Orthopedic Surgery" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospitals" />
      <FieldValue Value="Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Assistants" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physicians" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To evaluate the comparative effectiveness of early (&amp;lt;24 hours) versus late (&amp;gt;24 hours) open reduction and internal fixation of an open or closed femur fracture in trauma patients, particularly in preventing mortality, infection, nonunion/malunion, amputation, and venous thromboembolism (VTE)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trauma patients with an open or closed femur fracture&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Open reduction and internal fixation within 24 hours of injury &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Open reduction and internal fixation greater than 24 hours after injury (not recommended) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Mortality &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Infection &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Nonunion/malunion &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Amputation &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Venous thromboembolism (VTE) &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Primary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Secondary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Inclusion Criteria for This Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study Types&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For the purpose of making recommendations, studies included randomized controlled trials (RCTs), prospective observational or retrospective studies, and case-control studies. Only studies pertaining to open reduction and internal fixation of open or closed femur fractures were included.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participant Types&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The panel included studies with adult patients, any sex, and with no restriction on inclusion of ethnicities or patients with comorbidities. Meta-analyses, case reports, letters, and reviews containing no original data or comments were excluded.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intervention Type&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The panel included studies comparing open reduction and internal fixation performed within 24 hours from the time of injury to stabilization performed greater than 24 hours after injury.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Outcome Measure Types&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An initial list of all relevant outcomes (infection, nonunion/ malunion, compartment syndrome, venous thromboembolism (VTE), fat embolism syndrome, regional pain, neurologic impairment, arthritis, hardware failure, impaired function, mortality, or amputation) was generated and distributed to panelists. Eight panelists independently rated the relative importance of each outcome on a 9-point scale ranging from 1 (less important) to 9 (critically important for decision making). The five highest rated outcomes were selected as follows: mortality, infection, VTE, nonunion/malunion, and amputation. A systematic review of the literature was then conducted to identify relevant articles. Each article was evaluated independently by three members of the committee to extract pertinent data. The panel did not find any articles with data regarding the outcomes of nonunion/malunion and amputation, so these outcomes were excluded from the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Other outcomes considered were respiratory complications of fixation such as adult respiratory distress syndrome, fat embolism, pneumonia, and other pulmonary dysfunction. However, these outcomes were not included in this review.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Review Methods&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Search Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The literature search and appraisal were based on guidelines for systematic reviews. A MEDLINE and Cochrane search was conducted to identify English language human subjects prospective RCTs, non-RCTs, existing systematic reviews, guidelines, case-control, and observational studies published before November 2013. Search terms included (1) &lt;em&gt;femoral fractures&lt;/em&gt;, (2) &lt;em&gt;long bone stabilization&lt;/em&gt;, (3) &lt;em&gt;timing fixation&lt;/em&gt;, (4) &lt;em&gt;delayed fixation&lt;/em&gt;, (5) &lt;em&gt;early fixation&lt;/em&gt;, (6) &lt;em&gt;immediate fixation&lt;/em&gt;, (7) &lt;em&gt;fracture fixation&lt;/em&gt;, (8) &lt;em&gt;timing fracture&lt;/em&gt;, and (9) &lt;em&gt;timing osteosynthesis&lt;/em&gt;, alone or in combination. In addition to the electronic search, the bibliographies of relevant articles and systematic reviews were hand searched to find additional potentially appropriate publications to be included in this review.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Study Selection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A single panelist conducted the literature search and assessed the titles and abstracts to identify relevant publications, applying inclusion criteria. Case reports and review articles were excluded. The resulting studies then underwent full-text review by three independent reviewers to determine appropriateness for inclusion.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The panel retrieved 9,091 articles during the first phase of the literature search, of which 9,032 were excluded by duplicate removal and title review (see Figure 1 in the original guideline document). Fifty-nine articles addressing optimal timing of long bone fracture stabilization underwent a full review to identify 11 studies comparing early (&amp;lt;24 hours) versus late (&amp;gt;24 hours) open reduction and internal fixation of femur fractures in trauma patients.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of the 11 studies identified, 1 was a prospective randomized study and 10 were retrospective cohort studies.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation (GRADE) Methodology Levels for Rating the Quality of Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation (GRADE) Methodology Levels for Rating the Quality of Evidence&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Quality Level&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th class=&quot;Center&quot; valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;High&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Very confident that the true effect lies close to estimate of effect.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Moderate&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Moderate effect; true effect is likely close to estimate of effect but may be substantially different.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Low&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Limited confidence; true effect may be substantially different from estimate of effect&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Very Low&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Little confidence; true effect likely substantially different from estimate of effect.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Meta-Analysis" />
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review with Evidence Tables" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Extraction and Management&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Data were extracted by a single reviewer, confirmed by two other reviewers, and entered into Review Manager X.6 (RevMan). Information included authorship, publication year, methodology of the study, population, intervention, and relevant outcome measures.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Methodological Quality Assessment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The articles were evaluated using the Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development and Evaluation (GRADE) system. The quality of evidence was classified as high, moderate, low, or insufficient for each outcome (see the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence&quot; field). The quality of evidence is reflected as the extent to which one can be confident that an estimate of effect is correct and includes an explicit consideration of the following domains: risk of bias, inconsistency, indirectness, imprecision, and publication bias.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Measures of Treatment Effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The panel created a detailed set of evidence tables containing all abstracted information. Clinical outcomes, including mortality, infection, and venous thromboembolism (VTE) reported in each included study, were individually pooled for meta-analysis. The relative risk (RR) and 95% confidence interval (CI) were calculated for each study using a random-effects model. A &lt;em&gt;p&lt;/em&gt; &amp;lt; 0.05 was considered significant for all analyses. STATA 12.1 (College Station, TX) statistical analysis software was used for all statistical analyses. There were not enough data to undertake meta-analysis for the other two outcomes (nonunion/malunion and amputations).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Assessment of Heterogeneity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Potential heterogeneity existed because of population differences, different types of surgery, and how patients were defined. The panel examined these differences across studies to assess clinical and methodological heterogeneity. For the meta-analysis, they used RevMan to calculate the I2 statistic to determine the proportion of variation between studies attributable to heterogeneity, and variation was categorized as &quot;low&quot; (&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;=25%-49%), &quot;moderate&quot; (&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;=50%-74%), or &quot;high&quot; (&lt;em&gt;I&lt;/em&gt;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;=74%-100%).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recommendations were developed based on the results of the meta-analysis as well as the quality of evidence, and per the Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) approach, they were classified as either &quot;strong&quot; or &quot;weak&quot; (see the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;These recommendations were based on the quality of evidence and the risk-versus-benefit ratio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grading of Recommendations Assessment Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) ​​Definition of Strong and Weak Recommendation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table border=&quot;1&quot; cellspacing=&quot;1&quot; cellpadding=&quot;3&quot; summary=&quot;Table: Grading of Recommendations Assessment Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) ​​Definition of Strong and Weak Recommendation&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Strong Recommendation&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;            &lt;th valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;col&quot;&gt;Weak/Conditional Recommendation&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;    &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;For patients&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Most patients would want the recommended course of action.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Most patients would want the recommended course of action, but many would not.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;For clinicians&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Most patients should receive the recommended course of action.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Different choices will exist for different patients, and clinicians should help patients decide. &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;        &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; scope=&quot;row&quot;&gt;For policy makers &lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Recommended course should be adopted as policy.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;            &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot;&gt;Considerable debate and stakeholder involvement needed to make policy.&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;        &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A formal cost analysis was not performed and published cost analyses were not reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All authors participated in the critical review of the original guideline document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The type of supporting evidence is identified and graded for each recommendation (see the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Proponents of early stabilization point to more desirable outcomes, such as fewer complications, shorter hospital stays, and lower costs of care&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opponents suggest that early definitive stabilization may not be safe for the most severely injured patients or those with associated head, chest, or serious abdominal injuries due to increased blood loss, surgical stress, and pulmonary complications and that these and other factors may lead to increased mortality. Several other researchers have suggested a lack of benefit to early stabilization.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST) is a multi-disciplinary professional society committed to improving the care of injured patients. The Ad hoc Committee for Practice Management Guideline Development of EAST develops and disseminates evidence-based information to increase the scientific knowledge needed to enhance patient and clinical decision-making, improve health care quality, and promote efficiency in the organization of public and private systems of health care delivery. Unless specifically stated otherwise, the opinions expressed and statements made in this publication reflect the authors' personal observations and do not imply endorsement by nor official policy of EAST. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;&quot;Clinical practice guidelines are systematically developed statements to assist practitioner and patient decisions about appropriate health care for specific clinical circumstances.&quot;* These guidelines are not fixed protocols that must be followed, but are intended for health care professionals and providers to consider. While they identify and describe generally recommended courses of intervention, they are not presented as a substitute for the advice of a physician or other knowledgeable health care professional or provider. Individual patients may require different treatments from those specified in a given guideline. Guidelines are not entirely inclusive or exclusive of all methods of reasonable care that can obtain/produce the same results. While guidelines can be written that take into account variations in clinical settings, resources, or common patient characteristics, they cannot address the unique needs of each patient nor the combination of resources available to a particular community or health care professional or provider. Deviations from clinical practice guidelines may be justified by individual circumstances. Thus, guidelines must be applied based on individual patient needs using professional judgment. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;This guideline represents a very detailed summary of the literature regarding open reduction and internal fixation of femur fractures and surgical timing and is meant to inform the decision-making process, not replace clinical judgment. The optimal timing for internal fixation remains controversial. &lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;* Institute of Medicine. Clinical practice guidelines: directions for a new program. MJ Field and KN Lohr (eds) Washington, DC: National Academy Press. 1990: pg 39.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An implementation strategy was not provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Timeliness " />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Gandhi RR, Overton TL, Haut ER, Lau B, Vallier HA, Rohs T, Hasenboehler E, Lee JK, Alley D, Watters J, Rogers FB, Shafi S. Optimal timing of femur fracture stabilization in polytrauma patients: a practice management guideline from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2014 Nov;77(5):787-95. [51 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2000 (revised 2014 Nov)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma - Professional Association" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST) Practice Management Guidelines Committee&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Authors&lt;/em&gt;: Rajesh R. Gandhi, MD, Department of Surgery, JPS Health Network, Fort Worth, Texas; Tiffany L. Overton, MPH, Department of Surgery, JPS Health Network, Fort Worth, Texas; Elliott R. Haut, MD, PhD, Department of Surgery, The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland; Brandyn Lau, MPH, Department of Surgery, The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland; Heather A. Vallier, MD, Department of Orthopaedics, MetroHealth, Cleveland, Ohio; Thomas Rohs, MD, Department of Surgery, Borgess Health, Kalamazoo, Michigan; Erik Hasenboehler, MD, Department of Orthopaedic Surgery, The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, Baltimore, Maryland; Jane Kayle Lee, MD, Department of Surgery, Advocate Medical Group, Chicago, Illinois; Darrell Alley, MD, Department of Surgery, East Texas Medical Center, Tyler, Texas; Jennifer Watters, MD, Department of Surgery, Oregon Health and Science University, Portland, Oregon; Frederick B. Rogers, MD, Department of Trauma and Acute Care Surgery, Lancaster General Health, Lancaster, Pennsylvania; Shahid Shafi, MD, Department of Surgery, JPS Health Network, Fort Worth, Texas&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;E.R.H. is the primary investigator and supported by a contract (CE-12- 11-4489) from the Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute (PCORI) entitled &quot;Preventing Venous Thromboembolism: Empowering Patients and Enabling Patient-Centered Care Via Health Information Technology.&quot; E.R.H. receives royalties from Lippincott, Williams, &amp;amp; Wilkins for a book, &quot;Avoiding Common ICU Errors,&quot; and has given expert witness testimony in various medical malpractice cases. E.R.H. is a member of the EAST Board of Directors and Chairs the EAST Guidelines Committee. R.R.J. is a speaker for Lifecell. E.H. is supported by grants from Synthes and Smith and Nephew and is a consultant for Synthes. E.H. is also a speaker for AO North America Faculty. B.L. is the co-principal investigator of a contract (CE-12-11-4489) with PCORI entitled &quot;Preventing Venous Thromboembolism: Empowering Patients and Enabling Patient-Centered Care Via Health Information Technology.&quot; H.A.V. is a member of the board for the Orthopaedic Trauma Association and Center for Orthopaedic Trauma Advancement. H.A.V. receives support for the METRC research consortium funded by the Department of Defense, the FAITH research study funded by the National Institute of Health, and the sacrum research study funded by the Orthopaedic Trauma Association. J.W. is supported by a grant to study acupuncture in the intensive care unit (ICU) by the Medical Research Foundation and receives travel expenses for PROPPR trial meetings. S.S., F.B.R., T.R., D.A., J.K.L., and T.L.O. have nothing to disclose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;EAST Practice Management Guidelines Work Group. Practice management guidelines for the optimal timing of long bone fracture stabilization. Winston-Salem (NC): Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST); 2000. 39 p. [25 references]&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Electronic copies: Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.east.org/resources/treatment-guidelines/optimal-timing-of-femur-fracture-stabilization-in-polytrauma-patients-update&quot; title=&quot;EAST Web site&quot;&gt;Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST) Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Print copies: Available from the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma Guidelines, c/o Tiffany L. Overton, MPH, JPS Health Network, Trauma Services, 1500 S Main St, Fort Worth, TX; email: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:toverton@jpshealth.org&quot;&gt;toverton@jpshealth.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Kerwin AJ, Haut ER, Burns JB, Como JJ, Haider A, Stassen N, Dahm P, Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma Practice Management Guidelines Ad Hoc Committee. The Eastern Association of the Surgery of Trauma approach to practice management guideline development using Grading of Recommendations Assessment, Development, and Evaluation (GRADE) methodology. J Trauma Acute Care Surg. 2012 Nov;73(5 Suppl 4):S283-7. Electronic copies: Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.east.org/content/documents/east_approach_to_grade.pdf&quot; title=&quot;EAST Web site&quot;&gt;Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None available&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This summary was completed by ECRI on September 17, 2001. The information was verified by the guideline developer on September 27, 2001. This summary was updated by ECRI Institute on February 13, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary is based on the original guideline, which is copyrighted by the Eastern Association for the Surgery of Trauma (EAST).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse™ (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>