<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Uterine septum: a guideline.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Practice Committee of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine. Uterine septum: a guideline. Fertil Steril. 2016 Sep 1;106(3):530-40. [59 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=27235766&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Definitions for the level of evidence (&lt;strong&gt;Level I-III&lt;/strong&gt;) and the strength of the evidence (&lt;strong&gt;Grade A-C&lt;/strong&gt;) are given at the end of the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Diagnosis of Septate Uterus&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is fair evidence that 3-D ultrasound, sonohysterography, and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) are good diagnostic tests for distinguishing a septate and bicornuate uterus when compared with laparoscopy/hysteroscopy. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade B&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;It is recommended that imaging with hysteroscopy should be used to diagnose uterine septa rather than laparoscopy with hysteroscopy because this approach is less invasive (&lt;strong&gt;Grade B&lt;/strong&gt;). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Limitations of the Literature&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;The data regarding reproductive implications of septate uteri and treatment effects are limited and comprised primarily of observational, principally descriptive studies without untreated control groups. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Does a Septum Impact Fertility?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is insufficient evidence to conclude that a uterine septum is associated with infertility. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Does Treating a Septum Improve Fertility in Infertile Women?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Several observational studies indicate that hysteroscopic septum incision is associated with improved clinical pregnancy rates in women with infertility. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Does a Septum Contribute to Pregnancy Loss or Adverse Pregnancy Outcome?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is fair evidence that a uterine septum contributes to miscarriage and preterm birth. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade B&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Some evidence suggests that a uterine septum may increase the risk of other adverse pregnancy outcomes such as malpresentation, intrauterine growth restriction, placental abruption, and perinatal mortality. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade B&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Does Treating a Septum Improve Obstetrical Outcomes?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Some limited studies indicate that hysteroscopic septum incision is associated with a reduction in subsequent miscarriage rates and improvement in live-birth rates in patients with a history of recurrent pregnancy loss. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Some limited studies indicate that hysteroscopic septum incision is associated with an improvement in live-birth rate in women with infertility or prior pregnancy loss. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Are Septum Characteristics Associated with Worse Reproductive Outcomes?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is insufficient evidence to conclude that obstetric outcomes are different when comparing the size as defined by length or width of uterine septa. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Surgery to Treat a Uterine Septum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is insufficient evidence to recommend a specific method for hysteroscopic septum incision. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;How Long After Surgical Treatment of a Uterine Septum Should a Woman Wait to Conceive?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Although the available evidence suggests that the uterine cavity is healed by 2 months postoperatively, there is insufficient evidence to advocate a specific length of time before a woman should conceive. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Should Preoperative Management to Thin the Endometrium Be Used?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is insufficient evidence for or against recommending danazol or gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonists to thin the endometrium prior to hysteroscopic septum incision. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Is Adhesion Prevention Needed?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary Statement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is insufficient evidence to recommend for or against adhesion prevention treatment, or any specific method following hysteroscopic septum incision. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;It is recommended that imaging or imaging with hysteroscopy should be used to diagnose uterine septa rather than laparoscopy with hysteroscopy because this approach is less invasive. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade B&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In a patient with infertility, prior pregnancy loss, or poor obstetrical outcome it is reasonable to consider septum incision. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;In a patient without infertility or prior pregnancy loss, it may be reasonable to consider septum incision following counseling regarding potential risks and benefits of the procedure. (&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Definitions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level of Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level I&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from at least one properly designed randomized, controlled trial.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level II-1&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from well-designed controlled trials without randomization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level II-2&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from well-designed cohort or case-control analytic studies, preferably from more than one center or research group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level II-3&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from multiple time series with or without the intervention. Dramatic results in uncontrolled trials might also be regarded as this type of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level III&lt;/strong&gt;: Opinions of respected authorities based on clinical experience, descriptive studies, or reports of expert committees.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength of Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade A&lt;/strong&gt;: There is good evidence to support the recommendations, either for or against.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade B&lt;/strong&gt;: There is fair evidence to support the recommendations, either for or against.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;: There is insufficient evidence to support the recommendations, either for or against.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None provided&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Septate uterus &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Infertility &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Pregnancy loss &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Diagnosis" />
      <FieldValue Value="Management" />
      <FieldValue Value="Treatment" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Obstetrics and Gynecology" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physician Assistants" />
      <FieldValue Value="Physicians" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;To&#xA;review the literature regarding septate&#xA;uterus and determine optimal indications&#xA;and methods of treatment for it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Women with a septate uterus&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Diagnosis/Evaluation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;3-D ultrasound &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Sonohysterography &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Imaging with hysteroscopy &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Treatment/Management&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Hysteroscopic septum incision &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Counseling regarding potential risks and benefits of septum incision &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p class=&quot;Note&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: The following interventions/practices were considered but there was insufficient evidence to make recommendations for or against: comparing the size (i.e., length or width) of uterine septa to determine obstetric outcomes; specific methods for hysteroscopic septum incision; specific lengths of time before a woman should conceive after septum incision; use of danazol or gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) agonists to thin the endometrium prior to hysteroscopic septum incision; adhesion prevention treatment; or any specific method following hysteroscopic septum incision.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Pregnancy rate &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Implantation rate &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Live-birth rate &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Miscarriage rate &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Risk of infertility &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Adverse pregnancy outcomes &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Primary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hand-searches of Published Literature (Secondary Sources)" />
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Description of Search&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This clinical practice guideline was based on a systematic review of the literature. Systematic literature searches of relevant articles were performed in the electronic database MEDLINE through PubMed in March and April 2015, with a filter for human subject research. No limit or filter was used for time period covered or English language, but articles were subsequently culled for English language.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A combination of the following medical subject headings or text words/keywords were used: abortion, adhesion, adhesions, arcuate, bicornuate, birth control pill, congenital anomalies, congenital anomaly, congenital abnormalities, congenital abnormality, contraceptive, danazol, detection, diagnose, diagnosis, hysterosalpingogram, hysteroscopic, hysteroscopy, infertility, intrauterine, laparoscopic, laparoscopy, live birth, Lupron, metroplasty, miscarriage, magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), outcome, perinatal outcome, perinatal outcomes, pregnancies, pregnancy, pregnancy loss, premature, preterm, progestin, repair, resection, resectoscope, septa, septal, septate, septum, sonohysterogram, surgery, treatment, ultrasonography, uteri, uterine, uterus.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Initially, titles and abstracts of potentially relevant articles were screened and reviewed for inclusion/exclusion criteria. Protocols and results of the studies were examined according to specific inclusion criteria. Only studies that met the inclusion criteria were assessed in the final analysis. Studies were eligible if they met one of the following criteria: primary evidence (clinical trials) that assessed the effectiveness of a procedure correlated with an outcome measure (pregnancy, implantation, or live-birth rates); meta-analyses; and relevant articles from bibliographies of identified articles.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four members of an independent task force reviewed the full articles of all citations that possibly matched the predefined selection criteria. Final inclusion or exclusion decisions were made on examination of the articles in full. Disagreements about inclusion among reviewers were discussed and solved by consensus or arbitration after consultation with an independent reviewer/epidemiologist.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary of Inclusion/Exclusion Criteria&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Inclusion Criteria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Level 1, II-1, II-2, II-3 studies; systematic reviews/meta-analyses &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Human studies &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;English &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Studies that report clinical (fertility and/or obstetrical) outcomes &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Studies that focus on septate, arcuate, bicornuate uterine anomalies and/or adhesions &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Exclusion Criteria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Level III studies: small series, case reports, reviews, opinions, off topic &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Animal studies &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Non-English &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Studies that focus on prevalence with no fertility and/or obstetrical outcome measures &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Studies that do not focus on septate uterus, but focus on unicornuate or didelphic uteri, or fibroids and polyps, or cervix and vagina, obstructed hemivagina and ipsilateral renal anomaly (OHVIRA) or Herlyn-Werner-Wunderlich (HWW), Asherman, Fryns, or Mayer-Rokitansky-K&amp;uuml;ster-Hauser (MRKH) syndrome &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Studies with a focus on amenorrhea, blood flow, cancer, dysmenorrhea, endometriosis, hemodynamics, menorrhagia, ovarian maldescent, polycystic ovary syndrome, surgical technique only, uterine horn, uterine prolapse, vascular endothelial growth factor (VEGF) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Studies with a focus on pediatric or postpartum population &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Studies with a focus on abdominal metroplasty &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Number of studies identified in an electronic search and&#xA;from examination of reference lists from primary and review&#xA;articles = 1,034; number of studies included = 204.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Level of Evidence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level I&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from at least one properly designed randomized, controlled trial.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level II-1&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from well-designed controlled trials without randomization.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level II-2&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from well-designed cohort or case-control analytic studies, preferably from more than one center or research group.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level II-3&lt;/strong&gt;: Evidence obtained from multiple time series with or without the intervention. Dramatic results in uncontrolled trials might also be regarded as this type of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Level III&lt;/strong&gt;: Opinions of respected authorities based on clinical experience, descriptive studies, or reports of expert committees.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Review of Published Meta-Analyses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review with Evidence Tables" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The quality of the evidence was evaluated using the grading system found in the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence&quot; field and is assigned for each reference in the bibliography of the original guideline document.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Systematic reviews/meta-analyses were individually considered and included if they followed a strict methodological process and assessed relevant evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The literature was reviewed to answer the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: decimal;&quot; start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Does a septum cause infertility? &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Does a septum contribute to adverse obstetrical outcomes? Adverse obstetrical outcomes are pregnancy loss (early and late), preterm birth, and intrauterine death. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Does treating a septum improve fertility? What method or technique improves outcomes? &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Does treating a septum improve obstetrical outcomes? (pregnancy loss, duration of pregnancy, rupture) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;How to diagnose a septum? Are there other methods as accurate as laparoscopy/hysteroscopy to diagnose a septum? &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Are some types of deformity associated with worse outcomes? (short/long; thin/thick) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;How long after septum repair should a woman wait to conceive? &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Should you give preoperative management (medications vs. nothing) to thin the endometrium? (danazol, Lupron, birth control pill, progestins) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Does adhesion prevention work? (treatment vs. nothing, estrogen therapy, Foley balloon, intrauterine device [IUD], barrier slurries) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Strength of Evidence&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade A&lt;/strong&gt;: There is good evidence to support the recommendations, either for or against.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade B&lt;/strong&gt;: There is fair evidence to support the recommendations, either for or against.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grade C&lt;/strong&gt;: There is insufficient evidence to support the recommendations, either for or against.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A formal cost analysis was not performed and published cost analyses were not  reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This document was reviewed by American Society for Reproductive Medicine members, and their input was considered in the preparation of the final document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The type of supporting evidence is identified and graded for each recommendation (see the &quot;Major Recommendations&quot; field).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;There is fair evidence that 3-D ultrasound, sonohysterography, and magnetic resonance imaging (MRI) are good diagnostic tests for distinguishing a septate and bicornuate uterus when compared with laparoscopy/hysteroscopy. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Several studies indicate that treating a uterine septum is associated with an improvement in live-birth rates in women with a history of prior pregnancy loss, recurrent pregnancy loss, or infertility. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;There have been 18 case reports in the literature of uterine&#xA;rupture during pregnancy or delivery following septum incision. Risk of subsequent pregnancy-related uterine rupture&#xA;is correlated with excessive septal excision, penetration of the&#xA;myometrium, uterine wall perforation, and excessive use of&#xA;cautery or laser energy during the initial septum incision&#xA;procedure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This report was developed under the direction of the Practice Committee of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine as a service to its members and other practicing clinicians. Although this document reflects appropriate management of a problem encountered in the practice of reproductive medicine, it is not intended to be the only approved standard of practice or to dictate an exclusive course of treatment. Other plans of management may be appropriate, taking into account the needs of the individual patient, available resources, and institutional or clinical practice limitations. The Practice Committee and the Board of Directors of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine have approved this report.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An implementation strategy was not provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="117" OrdBy="1015" ID="437" Name="Implementation Tools" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Staff Training/Competency Material" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Getting Better" />
      <FieldValue Value="Living with Illness" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Practice Committee of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine. Uterine septum: a guideline. Fertil Steril. 2016 Sep 1;106(3):530-40. [59 references] &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/entrez/query.fcgi?cmd=Retrieve&amp;db=pubmed&amp;dopt=Abstract&amp;list_uids=27235766&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;PubMed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2016 Sep 1" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="American Society for Reproductive Medicine - Nonprofit Organization" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;American Society for Reproductive Medicine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Practice Committee of the American Society for Reproductive Medicine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Committee Members&lt;/em&gt;: Samantha Pfeifer, MD; Samantha Butts, MD, MSCE; Daniel Dumesic, MD; Clarisa Gracia, MD, MSCE; Michael Vernon, PhD; Gregory Fossum, MD; Andrew La Barbera PhD, HCLD; Jennifer Mersereau, MD; Randall Odem, MD; Alan Penzias, MD; Margareta Pisarska, MD; Robert Rebar, MD; Richard Reindollar, MD; Mitchell Rosen, MD; Jay Sandlow, MD; Eric Widra, MD&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;All&#xA;Committee members disclosed commercial and financial relationships&#xA;with manufacturers or distributors of goods or services&#xA;used to treat patients. Members of the Committee who&#xA;were found to have conflicts of interest based on the relationships&#xA;disclosed did not participate in the discussion or development&#xA;of this document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fertstert.org/article/S0015-0282(16)61281-5/pdf&quot; title=&quot;Fertility and Sterility Web site&quot;&gt;Fertility and Sterility Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Continuing medical education (CME) credit related to this guideline is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://store.asrm.org/Default.aspx?TabID=1533&quot; title=&quot;American Society for Reproductive Medicine Web site&quot;&gt;American Society for Reproductive Medicine Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None provided&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on March 3, 2017. The information was not verified by the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary is based on the original guideline, which is subject to the guideline developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse™ (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>