<Version>
  <xmlSource>This XML content was developed by AHRQ's contractor ECRI Institute for the National Guideline Clearinghouse (NGC).</xmlSource>
  <Section SecID="390" OrdBy="100" Name="General">
    <Field FieldID="161" OrdBy="105" ID="391" Name="Guideline Title" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_title&quot;&gt;Guideline for safe use of energy-generating devices.&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="110" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Burlingame BL, Conner RL. Guideline for safe use of energy-generating devices. In: 2016 Guidelines for Perioperative Practice. Denver (CO): Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN); 2016 Sep. p. e49-e76. [183 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="115" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="420" OrdBy="300" Name="Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="151" OrdBy="310" ID="421" Name="Major Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note from the Association of perioperative Registered Nurses (AORN)&lt;/strong&gt;: The original guideline document provides guidance to the perioperative team for the safe use and maintenance of energy-generating devices. The types of energy addressed in this document include electricity delivered as radio-frequency waves, ultrasound, and laser. The devices that generate the energy include electrosurgical units (ESUs), electrocauteries, ultrasonic instruments, and lasers. The energy produced is transferred to the patient by various methods, including monopolar, bipolar, advanced bipolar (e.g., vessel-sealing), and tripolar (e.g., plasma knife) devices; class 3 and class 4 lasers; and ultrasound (e.g., ultrasonic tissue ablation system, phacoemulsification) and argon-enhanced coagulation (AEC) modalities.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol style=&quot;list-style-type: upper-roman;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Precautions should be taken to mitigate the risk for injury to patients and personnel during the use of energy-generating devices. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Precautions should be taken to mitigate the risk for injury associated with the use of electrosurgical units and electrosurgical accessories. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Precautions should be taken to mitigate the risk for injury associated with the use of electrosurgery during minimally invasive surgery. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;A laser safety program should be established for all owned, leased, or borrowed laser equipment in any location where lasers are used (ECRI, 2011; &quot;Z136.3: Safe use of lasers in health care,&quot; 2011; &quot;Z136.1: Safe use of lasers,&quot; 2014). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Precautions should be taken to mitigate the risk for injury associated with the use of a laser (Dhepe, 2009; Hospital eTools, 2016). &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Precautions should be taken to mitigate the risk for injury associated with the use of a phacoemulsifier. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Precautions should be taken to mitigate the risk of injury associated with the use of AEC. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="138" OrdBy="330" ID="423" Name="Clinical Algorithm(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None provided&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="396" OrdBy="400" Name="Scope">
    <Field FieldID="140" OrdBy="405" ID="397" Name="Disease/Condition(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any condition requiring surgical or other invasive procedures with use of energy-generating devices&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="103" OrdBy="410" ID="398" Name="Guideline Category" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Prevention" />
      <FieldValue Value="Risk Assessment" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="113" OrdBy="415" ID="399" Name="Clinical Specialty" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Nursing" />
      <FieldValue Value="Surgery" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="114" OrdBy="420" ID="400" Name="Intended Users" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Advanced Practice Nurses" />
      <FieldValue Value="Hospitals" />
      <FieldValue Value="Nurses" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="129" OrdBy="425" ID="401" Name="Guideline Objective(s)" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;To provide guidance to the perioperative team for the safe use and maintenance of energy-generating devices &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;To provide guidance for some elements of surgical fires and electrical safety related to energy-generating devices &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="132" OrdBy="430" ID="402" Name="Target Population" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Patients undergoing surgical and other invasive procedures that require use of energy-generating devices&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="133" OrdBy="435" ID="403" Name="Interventions and Practices Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Safe use and maintenance of energy-generating devices used in the perioperative environment including electrosurgical units (ESUs), electrocauteries, ultrasonic instruments, and lasers&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="134" OrdBy="440" ID="404" Name="Major Outcomes Considered" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Incidence of patient injury when using devices that generate the energy, such as electrosurgical units (ESUs), electrocauteries, ultrasonic instruments, and lasers &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Risk of injury to health care personnel &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="405" OrdBy="500" Name="Methodology">
    <Field FieldID="109" OrdBy="505" ID="406" Name="Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Searches of Electronic Databases" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="135" OrdBy="510" ID="407" Name="Description of Methods Used to Collect/Select the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;text-decoration: underline;&quot;&gt;Evidence Review&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A medical librarian conducted a systematic search of the databases MEDLINE&amp;reg;, CINAHL&amp;reg;, and Scopus&amp;reg; and the Cochrane Database of Systematic Reviews in October 2015. Results were limited to literature published in English from January 2009 through October 2015. The medical librarian also established alerts at the time of the initial search. During the development of the guideline, the lead author requested supplementary searches and additional articles that either did not fit the original search criteria or were discovered during the evidence appraisal process. The results of alerts were considered until February 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The search terms included subject headings and keywords that address precautions and injuries related to the use of electrosurgical and laser devices. Terms for procedures included &lt;em&gt;electrosurgery, ultrasonic therapy, ultrasonic surgical procedures, diathermy, argon plasma coagulation, electrocoagulation, high-intensity focused ultrasound ablation, endometrial ablation techniques, and laser therapy&lt;/em&gt;. Subject headings and keywords related to precautions included &lt;em&gt;adverse effects, accident prevention, patient safety, equipment contamination, equipment safety, equipment failure,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;risk management&lt;/em&gt;. Special attention was paid to terms that would retrieve literature addressing the potential causes and effects of equipment failure and injuries. Such terms included &lt;em&gt;burns, fires, implantable electronic devices&lt;/em&gt; (e.g., &lt;em&gt;artificial pacemaker, implanted electrodes, electromagnetic fields&lt;/em&gt;), and &lt;em&gt;power sources and settings&lt;/em&gt; (e.g., &lt;em&gt;electric power supplies, grounding, capacitive coupling, electric wiring&lt;/em&gt;). Subject headings and keywords for types of personal protective equipment and occupational hazards also were included.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Excluded were non-peer-reviewed publications, evidence from other disciplines when evidence from the perioperative setting was available, and case reports that did not provide recommendations for preventing injuries related to the use of electrosurgical devices. Editorials, news items, and other brief items were excluded. Lower-level or lower-quality evidence was excluded when higher-level or higher-quality evidence was available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="136" OrdBy="515" ID="408" Name="Number of Source Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;In total, 725 research and non-research sources of evidence were identified for possible inclusion, and of these, 183 were cited in the original guideline document. See Figure 1 in the original guideline document for a flow diagram of literature search results.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="115" OrdBy="520" ID="409" Name="Methods Used to Assess the Quality and Strength of the Evidence" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Weighting According to a Rating Scheme (Scheme Given)" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="149" OrdBy="525" ID="410" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;: Randomized controlled trial (RCT) or experimental study, systematic review of all RCTs&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;II&lt;/strong&gt;: Quasi-experimental study, systematic review of quasi-experimental studies or combination of quasi-experimental and RCTs&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;III&lt;/strong&gt;: Non-experimental studies, qualitative studies, systematic review of non-experimental studies, combination of non-experimental, quasi-experimental, and RCTs, or any or all studies are qualitative&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IV&lt;/strong&gt;: Clinical practice guidelines, position or consensus statements&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;V&lt;/strong&gt;: Literature review, expert opinion, case report, community standard, clinician experience, consumer experience, organizational experience (quality improvement, financial)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="116" OrdBy="530" ID="411" Name="Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Systematic Review with Evidence Tables" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="150" OrdBy="535" ID="412" Name="Description of the Methods Used to Analyze the Evidence" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Articles identified by the search were provided to the project team for evaluation. The team consisted of the lead author and three evidence appraisers. The lead author divided the search results into topics and assigned members of the team to review and critically appraise each article using the Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN) Research or Non-Research Evidence Appraisal Tools as appropriate. The literature was independently evaluated and appraised according to the strength and quality of the evidence. Each article was then assigned an appraisal score. The appraisal score is noted in brackets after each reference in the original guideline document, as applicable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="112" OrdBy="540" ID="413" Name="Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="Expert Consensus" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="145" OrdBy="545" ID="414" Name="Description of Methods Used to Formulate the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collective evidence supporting each intervention within a specific recommendation was summarized and the Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN) Evidence Rating Model (see the &quot;Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations&quot; field) was used to rate the strength of the evidence. Factors considered in the review of the collective evidence were the quality of the evidence, the quantity of similar evidence on a given topic, and the consistency of evidence supporting a recommendation. The evidence rating is noted in brackets after each intervention in the original guideline document.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="146" OrdBy="550" ID="415" Name="Rating Scheme for the Strength of the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1: Strong Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;: Interventions or activities for which effectiveness has been demonstrated by high quality evidence from rigorously-designed studies, meta-analyses, or systematic reviews, or rigorously-developed clinical practice guidelines&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Evidence from a meta-analysis or systematic review of research studies that incorporated evidence appraisal and synthesis of the evidence in the analysis &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Supportive evidence from a single well-conducted randomized controlled trial (RCT) &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Guidelines that are developed by a panel of experts, that derive from an explicit literature search methodology, and include evidence appraisal and synthesis of the evidence &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1: Regulatory Requirement&lt;/strong&gt;: Federal law or regulation&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2: High Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;: Interventions or activities for which effectiveness has been demonstrated by evidence from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Good quality systematic review of RCTs &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;High quality systematic review in which all studies are quasi-experimental or a combination of RCTs and quasi-experimental studies &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;High quality quasi-experimental study &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;High quality systematic review in which all studies are non-experimental or include a combination of RCTs, quasi-experimental, and non-experimental studies. Any or all studies may be qualitative. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;High quality non-experimental studies &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;High quality qualitative studies &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Good quality clinical practice guideline, consensus or position statement &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3: Moderate Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;: Interventions or activities for which the evidence has been demonstrated by evidence from:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Good quality systematic review in which all studies are quasi-experimental or a combination of RCTs and quasi-experimental studies &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Good quality quasi-experimental study &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;High or good quality literature review, case report, expert opinion, or organizational experience &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4: Limited Evidence&lt;/strong&gt;: Interventions or activities for which there are currently insufficient evidence or evidence of low quality&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Supportive evidence from a poorly conducted research study &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Evidence from non-experimental studies with high potential for bias &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Guidelines developed largely by consensus or expert opinion &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Non-research evidence with insufficient evidence or inconsistent results &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Conflicting evidence, but where the preponderance of the evidence supports the recommendation &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5: Benefits Balanced with Harms&lt;/strong&gt;: Selected interventions or activities for which the Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN) Guidelines Advisory Board is of the opinion that the desirable effects of following this recommendation outweigh the harms&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="148" OrdBy="565" ID="417" Name="Cost Analysis" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;A formal cost analysis was not performed and published cost analyses were not reviewed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="104" OrdBy="570" ID="418" Name="Method of Guideline Validation" Type="picklist-choice">
      <FieldValue Value="External Peer Review" />
      <FieldValue Value="Internal Peer Review" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="130" OrdBy="575" ID="419" Name="Description of Method of Guideline Validation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Guideline for Safe Use of Energy-Generating Devices has been approved by the Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN) Guidelines Advisory Board. It was presented as a proposed guideline for comments by members and others. The guideline is effective September 1, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="424" OrdBy="600" Name="Evidence Supporting the Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="98" OrdBy="605" ID="425" Name="References Supporting the Recommendations" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Dhepe N. Minimum standard guidelines of care on requirements for setting up a laser room. Indian J Dermatol Venereol Leprol. 2009;75 (Suppl 2):S101-S110.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;ECRI Institute. Laser use and safety. Oper Room Risk Manag. 2011:IA.&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Hospital eTools. Surgical suite - use of medical lasers.Washington (DC): Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA); [accessed 2016 Jun 27]. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Z136.1: Safe use of lasers. In: ANSI Z136 Standards. Orlando (FL): Laser Institute of America; 2014. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Z136.3: Safe use of lasers in health care. In: ANSI Z136 Standards. Orlando (FL): Laser Institute of America; 2011. &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="139" OrdBy="610" ID="426" Name="Type of Evidence Supporting the Recommendations" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The literature was independently evaluated and appraised according to the strength and quality of the evidence. Each article was then assigned an appraisal score. The appraisal score is noted in brackets after each reference in the original guideline document, as applicable. Also see the original guideline document for the systematic review and discussion of evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="427" OrdBy="700" Name="Benefits/Harms of Implementing the Guideline Recommendations">
    <Field FieldID="152" OrdBy="705" ID="428" Name="Potential Benefits" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Risk of injury to surgical patients and perioperative personnel will be reduced. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Refer to the original guideline document for additional discussion of potential benefits of specific interventions. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="153" OrdBy="710" ID="429" Name="Potential Harms" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not stated&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="432" OrdBy="900" Name="Qualifying Statements">
    <Field FieldID="137" OrdBy="905" ID="433" Name="Qualifying Statements" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;These recommendations represent the Association's official position on questions regarding optimal perioperative nursing practice. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;No attempt has been made to gain consensus among users, manufacturers, and consumers of any material or product. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Compliance with the Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN) guideline is voluntary. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AORN's recommendations are intended as achievable and represent what is believed to be an optimal level of patient care within surgical and invasive procedure settings. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Although they are considered to represent the optimal level of practice, variations in practice settings and clinical situations may limit the degree to which each recommendation can be implemented. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;AORN recognizes the many diverse settings in which perioperative nurses practice; therefore, this guideline is adaptable to all areas where operative or other invasive procedures may be performed. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="434" OrdBy="1000" Name="Implementation of the Guideline">
    <Field FieldID="131" OrdBy="1010" ID="436" Name="Description of Implementation Strategy" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;An implementation strategy was not provided.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="117" OrdBy="1015" ID="437" Name="Implementation Tools" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Mobile Device Resources" />
      <FieldValue Value="Resources" />
      <FieldValue Value="Staff Training/Competency Material" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="439" OrdBy="1100" Name="Institute of Medicine (IOM) National Healthcare Quality Report Categories">
    <Field FieldID="50" OrdBy="1105" ID="440" Name="IOM Care Need" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Staying Healthy" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="51" OrdBy="1110" ID="441" Name="IOM Domain" Type="picklist-many">
      <FieldValue Value="Effectiveness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Patient-centeredness" />
      <FieldValue Value="Safety" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="442" OrdBy="1200" Name="Identifying Information and Availability">
    <Field FieldID="97" OrdBy="1201" ID="392" Name="Bibliographic Source(s)" Type="citation">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;table&gt;&lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt;Burlingame BL, Conner RL. Guideline for safe use of energy-generating devices. In: 2016 Guidelines for Perioperative Practice. Denver (CO): Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN); 2016 Sep. p. e49-e76. [183 references]&lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="124" OrdBy="1205" ID="443" Name="Adaptation" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Not applicable: The guideline was not adapted from another source.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="128" OrdBy="1215" ID="445" Name="Date Released" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="2016 Sep" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="158" OrdBy="1225" ID="447" Name="Guideline Developer(s)" Type="orglist-p">
      <FieldValue Value="Association of periOperative Registered Nurses - Professional Association" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="125" OrdBy="1235" ID="449" Name="Source(s) of Funding" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="126" OrdBy="1240" ID="450" Name="Guideline Committee" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN) Guidelines Advisory Board&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="127" OrdBy="1245" ID="451" Name="Composition of Group That Authored the Guideline" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lead Author&lt;/em&gt;: Byron L. Burlingame, MS, BSN, RN, CNOR, Senior Perioperative Nursing Specialist, AORN Nursing Department, Denver, Colorado&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Contributing Author&lt;/em&gt;: Ramona L. Conner, MSN, RN, CNOR, Editor-in-Chief, Guidelines for Perioperative Practice, AORN Nursing Department, Denver, Colorado&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Team Members&lt;/em&gt;: Janice Neil, PhD, RN, CNE, Associate Professor, College of Nursing, East Carolina University, Greenville, North Carolina; Mary Lamonte, MPH, MSN, RN, CNOR, Staff Nurse, Stamford Surgical Center, Stamford, Connecticut; Barbara Nalley, MSN, CRNP, CNOR, RN First Assistant, Jackson Surgical Assistant, Crofton, Maryland; Melanie Sandoval, PhD, RN, ACNP, Perioperative Research Nurse Scientist, University of Colorado Hospital, Aurora, Colorado; Jane Flowers, MSN, RN, CNOR, NEA-BC, Nurse Manager, Shore Health System, Easton, Maryland&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="147" OrdBy="1250" ID="452" Name="Financial Disclosures/Conflicts of Interest" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;No financial relationships relevant to the content of this guideline have been disclosed by the authors, planners, peer reviewers, or staff.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="120" OrdBy="1256" ID="393" Name="Guideline Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the current release of the guideline.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This guideline meets NGC's 2013 (revised) inclusion criteria.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="118" OrdBy="1260" ID="454" Name="Guideline Availability" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Available to subscribers from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aorn.org/eSubscription/&quot; title=&quot;AORN Web site&quot;&gt;Association of periOperative Nurses Web (AORN) site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Print copies: Available for purchase from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aorn.org/guidelines/purchase-guidelines/print-edition&quot; title=&quot;AORN Web site&quot;&gt;AORN Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="119" OrdBy="1265" ID="455" Name="Availability of Companion Documents" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following is available:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;ul style=&quot;list-style-type: disc;&quot;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;    &lt;li&gt;Evidence table. Guideline for safe use of energy-generating devices. 2016 Sept. 15 p. Available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aorn.org/guidelines/about-aorn-guidelines/evidence-tables&quot; title=&quot;AORN Web site&quot;&gt;Association of periOperative Nurses (AORN) Web site&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/li&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Additional implementation tools, including online learning modules, videos and community discussions, are available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aorn.org/guidelines/guideline-implementation-topics/equipment-and-product-safety/electrosurgery&quot; title=&quot;AORN Web site&quot;&gt;AORN Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Documents related to the evidence rating model, hierarchy of evidence, and expanded appraisal tools are available from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.aorn.org/guidelines/about-aorn-guidelines/evidence-rating&quot; title=&quot;AORN Web site&quot;&gt;AORN Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In addition, an AORN Guidelines for Perioperative Practice eBook mobile app is available from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aorn.org/guidelines/purchase-guidelines/ebook-mobile-app&quot; title=&quot;AORN Web site&quot;&gt;AORN Web site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="143" OrdBy="1275" ID="457" Name="Patient Resources" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;None available&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="142" OrdBy="1280" ID="458" Name="NGC Status" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary was completed by ECRI Institute on March 7, 2017. The information was not verified by the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
    <Field FieldID="141" OrdBy="1290" ID="460" Name="Copyright Statement" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;div class=&quot;content_para&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;This NGC summary is based on the original guideline, which is subject to the guideline developer's copyright restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
  <Section SecID="99999" OrdBy="99999" Name="Disclaimer">
    <Field FieldID="99999" OrdBy="99999" ID="99999" Name="NGC Disclaimer" Type="text">
      <FieldValue Value="&lt;p&gt;The National Guideline Clearinghouse™ (NGC) does not develop, produce, approve, or endorse the guidelines represented on this site.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;All guidelines summarized by NGC and hosted on our site are produced under the auspices of medical specialty societies, relevant professional associations, public or private organizations, other government agencies, health care organizations or plans, and similar entities.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Guidelines represented on the NGC Web site are submitted by guideline developers, and are screened solely to determine that they meet the &lt;a href=&quot;/help-and-about/summaries/inclusion-criteria&quot;&gt;NGC Inclusion Criteria&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;NGC, AHRQ, and its contractor ECRI Institute make no warranties concerning the content or clinical efficacy or effectiveness of the clinical practice guidelines and related materials represented on this site. Moreover, the views and opinions of developers or authors of guidelines represented on this site do not necessarily state or reflect those of NGC, AHRQ, or its contractor ECRI Institute, and inclusion or hosting of guidelines in NGC may not be used for advertising or commercial endorsement purposes.&lt;/p&gt; &#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Readers with questions regarding guideline content are directed to contact the guideline developer.&lt;/p&gt;" />
    </Field>
  </Section>
</Version>